世界真的是大变样了
Things are never gonna be the same now.
你看看这幅画
I mean, look at this.
画中有外星人
You got aliens.
还有这个绿色的大家伙 拆毁了不少大楼
You got big green guys tearing down buildings.
我小的时候画的还是牛仔和印第安人
When I was a kid, I used to draw cowboys and Indians.
应该把他们叫做 "美洲土著居民" 但是…
Actually, it's native American, but whatever.
嗯 不管怎么说
Yeah. Tell you what, though.
画的还可以吧
It ain't bad, is it?
是啊 还行
No. Yeah.
这孩子挺有前途的
Kid's got a future.
嗯…
Yeah, well,
也许吧
we'll see, I guess.
嘿 停下
No, hey! Ah!
你这样是锯不开那玩意的
You can't saw through that stuff.
这些外星垃圾很难搞的
These alien bastards are tough.
你要用他们用的工具
You gotta use the stuff they use.
- 看到了没 就这样搞 - 明白了
- See? All right. - All right.
嘿
Oh, hey!
这都下午了 可算把你盼来了
Glad you could join us. Afternoon.
- 我的闹钟没响 - 是啊 是啊 你闹钟的问题
- Yeah. My alarm didn't go off. - Yeah, your alarm.
听着 按我说的那样 把那些装甲堆起来就好
Look, just go stack that armor plating like I asked you.
这可是很大的一单生意
This is a huge deal for us.
请注意
Attention, please!
根据行政令396B号
In accordance with executive order 396b,
所有的战后清理行动
all post-battle cleanup operations
现在由我们负责
are now under our jurisdiction.
多谢你们的劳动 从今以后这就归我们管了
Thank you for your service. We'll take it from here.
你是谁啊
Who the hell are you?
我们是有资格的处理人员
Qualified personnel.
听着 我是签了合同的
Look, I have a city contract
负责清理城市里的这些玩意 我和市政府签了合同的
to salvage all this, okay, with the city, so...
抱歉 图姆斯先生 但是现在所有的城市清理工作
I apologize, Mr. toomes, but all salvage operations
都由我们负责了
are now under our jurisdiction.
请交出你们所有收集的外星材料
Please turn over any and all exotic materials
否则你会受到起诉
that you've collected or you will be prosecuted.
女士 你…
Ma'am, what am...?
请等一下
Please. Come here. Hey, lady, come on.
听我说
Look...
为了干这活我买了卡车
I bought trucks for this job.
还雇了一伙人
I brought in a whole new crew.
他们都要养家糊口 我也要养活自己的家人
These guys have a family. I have a family.
我已经在这上面投入了一切 我不能就这么丢了房子
I'm all in on this. I could lose my house.
很抱歉 先生 对此我无能为力
I'm sorry, sir. There's nothing I can do.
下次 别这么不自量力了
Maybe next time, don't overextend yourself.
你说什么
What'd you say?
是啊
Yeah.
他说得对 我是不自量力
He's right. I overextended myself.
- 嘿 - 别乱来
- Hey, hey, hey. - Don't do it.
把枪放下
Ah-ah-ah-ah. Put 'em down.
如果你有什么意见
If you have a grievance,
可以去找我的上级
you may take it up with my superiors.
你的上级 你他妈的上级是谁啊
Your superiors. Who the hell are they?
史塔克工业与联邦政府共同建立的合资企业
A joint venture between stark industries
灾害控制部
and the federal government, the department
将会监督 外星及其它特殊材料的
of damage control, will oversee the collection
收集与存储过程
and storage of alien and other exotic materials.
罪魁祸首收拾自己的烂摊子 还有钱拿
Now the assholes who made this mess are paid to clean it up.
是啊 都是黑幕
Yeah, it's all rigged.
专家估计 有超过1500吨的外星材料
Experts estimate there are over 1500 tons of exotic material
分布在三州地区
scattered throughout the tri-state area.
头儿
Hey, chief!
我这还有一车昨天留下的东西
We still have another load from yesterday.
我们是不是应该把这些上交
We're supposed to turn this in, right?
- 我是不打算搬过去了 - 真是太可惜了
- I ain't hauling it. - It's too bad.
咱可以用这些外星垃圾造很多不错的玩意
We could have made some cool stuff from all that alien junk.
要我说
I tell you what.
咱们就把它们留下来吧
Let's keep it.
世界在改变
The world's changing.
我们也是时候改变了
It's time we change too.
八年后
成功了 梅森
There you go, Mason.
是啊
Yeah!
生意不错
Business is good.
纽约 皇后区 这个街区治安不好
New York. Queens. It's a rough borough,
- 但那是我的家 - 你在跟谁说话
- but, hey, it's home. - Who you talking to?
没呢 只是录一些这次旅行的短视频
No one. Just making a little video of the trip.
- 你应该知道 你不能把它给别人看吧 - 我知道的
- You can't show it to anyone. - Yeah, I know.
那你为什么还要给视频作解说呢
Then why are you narrating in that voice?
- 因为这挺有意思的 - "挺有意思"
- Uh, because it's fun. - Fun.
为什么他们都叫你 "哈皮"呢
So why do they call you happy?
快点 我不会帮你扛包的 我们走
Come on. I'm not carrying your bags. Let's go.
嘿 坐飞机前我是不是得先上个厕所
Hey, should I go to the bathroom before?
飞机上有厕所
There's a bathroom on it.
哇 无人驾驶 这么酷啊
Whoa. No pilot? That's awesome.
- 你就打算坐这么 - 对
- Is that where you're gonna sit? - Yeah.
你这是第一次坐私人飞机么
This is your first time on a private plane?
这是我第一次坐飞机
My first time on any plane.
这个声音正常么
Should it...? Should it be...? Should it be making that noise?
嘘
Shh, shh, shh.
其实现在还没人跟我说清楚
No one has actually told me
为什么要我来柏林 要我来干什么
why I'm in Berlin or what I'm doing.
好像是什么 美国队长发疯了
Something about captain America going crazy.
- 你住这间 - 你住我隔壁啊
- This is you. - Oh, we're neighbors?
我们不住一起 去把装备穿上
We're not roommates. Suit up.
放松 彼得 你能搞定的
Okay, Peter, you got this.
你这是穿的啥呢
What the hell are you wearing?
我的装备啊
It's my suit.
- 那个箱子呢 - 什么箱子
- Where's the case? - What case?
这不是我…我还以为这是个衣橱呢
What? I thought that was a closet.
- 那边也是我的房间么 - 快进去
- This is still my room? - Go. Please.
- 我的房间比我想象的要大… - 在那呢
- My room is way bigger than... - there.
我找到他说的那个箱子了
I found the case. I found the case.
"一点小升级"
"A minor upgrade"?
哇
Whoa.
我的天
Oh, my god.
穿上啊
Put it on. What the...?
这是我见过的 最酷的东西
This is the coolest thing I've ever seen...
- 动作快点 - 我不明白…
- Let's go. - But I don't understand.
这是给我的么 哈皮 哈皮 等等我
Is it for me? Happy. Happy, wait.
这简直太疯狂了 太疯狂了
This is insane. Insane.
看看这玩意 看看这眼睛
Look at this thing. Look. Look at the eyes.
- 这是我人生中最棒的一天 - 快走吧
- The greatest day of my life. - Let's go. Come on.
那里是 美国队长 钢铁侠 黑寡妇
Okay, there's captain America, iron man, black widow.
- 哇 那个新人是谁 - 小蜘蛛
- Whoa. Who's that new guy? - Underoos!
叫我了 我要走了 我要上场了
Oh, that's me. I gotta go. I gotta go.
嘿 各位
Hey, everyone.
刚刚的事简直太疯狂了
Okay, so the craziest thing just happeNed.
我和美国队长打起来了
I just had a fight with captain America.
我偷了他的盾牌 然后把它扔向了他
I stole his shield. I threw it at him...
什么情况…他变大了 我要走了 待会继续
what the hell? He's big now. I gotta go. Hang on.
刚刚发生的事简直太惊人了
It was the most amazing thing!
史塔克先生叫道 "嘿 小蜘蛛"
Mr. stark was like, "hey, underoos!"
我就一个跟头翻过去 把美国队长的盾给偷了
I flipped in and stole cap's shield.
然后我就说 "嘿 大家好啊"
I was like, "what's up, everybody?"
等一下 来了
And then... hey, just a second! Coming!
这里的墙不隔音
We have thin walls here.
你在干什么 做视频日记么
What are you doing, a little video diary?
- 对 - 好吧
- Yeah. - It's all right.
- 我会做同样的事 - 我跟他说过不要录
- I'd do the same thing. - I told him not to.
但他还是一直在录 我要把那些玩意都删了
He was filming. I'm gonna wipe the chip.
其实
Okay. Hey. You know what?
我们也应该给你姨妈
We should make an alibi video
录一个证明你不在场的视频 准备好了么
for your aunt anyway. You ready?
- 行 当然可以 - 靠近点 我们俩都上镜
- An alibi? Sure. Okay. - We rolling? Get in the frame.
嘿 梅 在忙什么
Hey, may. How you doing?
你穿的是什么呢 这么暴露
What are you wearing? Something skimpy, I hope.
彼得 之前这段不太合适
Peter, that's inappropriate.
再来一次 把前面的删掉
Let's start over. You can edit it.
三二一 开始 嘿 梅
Three, two, one. Hey, may.
我的天… 就是想告诉你
My gosh, I wanted to tell you
你的外甥周末
what an incredible job your nephew did
在史塔克工业实习 表现出色
this weekend at the stark internship retreat.
给大家留下了深刻印象
Everyone was impressed.
- 我靠 - 刚刚经过了个岔道 抱歉
- Come on! - It's a freaking merge. Sorry.
因为你没走皇后大道 所以才有这么多情况
Because you're not on queens boulevard.
哈皮的梦想就是
See, happy is hoping
当上资产管理人
to get bumped up to asset management.
他原来是安保人员 再之前 当过一段时间的司机
He was forehead of security, before that he was a driver.
那是我们之间的私人谈话
That was a private conversation.
我不喜欢拿这个开玩笑 我考虑了很久才告诉你的…
I don't like joking about this. It was hard to talk about that.
说真的 他在飞机上打呼噜了么
No, seriously, was he snoring a bunch?
好了 我们到了…
Here we are. End of the line. Whoops.
- 哈皮 能让我们单独待一会么 - 你想让我下车
- Can you give us a moment? - Want me to leave the car?
去把彼得的东西从行李箱拿出来
Grab Peter's case out of the trunk.
我能留着那套装备
I can keep the suit?
是啊 我刚刚才跟你说的
Yes, we were just talking about it.
我跟你说
Do me a favor, though.
哈皮就算你的联系人了
Happy's kind of your point guy on this.
别让他太紧张 别做什么傻事
Don't stress him out. Don't do anything stupid.
我看过他的心电图
I've seen his cardiogram.
- 好么 - 好
- All right? - Yes.
别做什么我会去做的事
Don't do anything I would do,
当然 我不做的事你千万别做
and don't do anything i wouldn't do.
你所做的那些事处于灰色地带
There's a little gray area in there. Where you operate.
等下 是不是我这就加入了复仇者联盟
Wait, does that mean I'm an avenger?
不是
No.
- 他住几楼 - 七楼
- This it? - Seventh floor.
我能自己拿上去 不用麻烦你了
I can take that. You don't have to.
- 你要自己拿上去么 - 嗯 我自己拿
- You'll take it? - Yeah, I can take that.
谢谢你
Thank you.
所以 我下一次…
So when's our next...?
下一次 "实习" 是什么时候 你懂的
When's our next "retreat," you know?
什么 你说的是下次任务么
What, next mission?
是的 任务 任务
Yeah, the mission. The missions.
- 我会联系你的 - 那你有我的电话号码么
- We'll call you. - Do you have my numbers?
不 我的意思是 我们会联系你
No, I mean, we'll call you.
就像其他人打电话给你 也是联系你 明白了吧
Like, someone will call you. All right?
- 以后我们就是一队的了 - 好的
- From your team. - Okay. All right.
这不是拥抱 我只是帮你打开车门
That's not a hug. I'm just grabbing
我们的关系 还没到那么亲密呢
the door for you. We're not there yet.
再见
Bye.
他们会联系我的
They're gonna call me.
两个月后
哈皮 就是跟你汇报一下 我2：45放学
已经准备好参加下次任务了
顺便说一句我是彼得
帕克
你好啊 屁颠儿 帕克
What's up, penis Parker?
市科技中学的同学们 大家早上好
Rise and shine, midtown science and technology.
大家别忘记带校友返校日活动的门票哟
Students, don't forget about your homecoming tickets.
你有约好一起参加活动的人么
Do you have a date for homecoming?
谢谢 杰森 我已经有伴了
Thanks, Jason, but I already have a date.
- 好吧 - 嗯
- Okay. - Yeah.
你马上来我的办公室
Damn it. You, in my office right now.
咱们一起
Join me, and together
用乐高积木搭一个新的死星模型吧
we'll build my new lego death star.
- 你说什么 - 真蹩脚
- What? - So lame.
不会吧 这么牛 总共要多少块积木
No way. That's awesome. How many pieces?
3803块
Three thousand eight hundred and three.
- 真是太疯狂了 - 是的
- That's insane. - I know.
我们今晚一起搭么
You want to build it tonight?
今晚没空啊 我要去史塔克工业实习
No, I can't tonight. I've got the stark...
- 去实习啊 - 是啊 没错
- mm-hm. Stark internship. - Yeah, exactly.
哥们 你都找到实习了
Always got that internship.
不久后
Yeah, well, hopefully,
还有希望转为正式工作呢
soon it'll lead to a real job with them.
- 那可真是太棒了 - 对啊
- That would be so sweet. - Right?
你的老板会说
He'd be all,
"表格做的不错 彼得 这是给你的金币"
"good job on those spreadsheets, Peter. Here's a gold coin."
- 我对工作没概念 - 就是你说的这样
- I don't know how jobs work. - That's exactly how they work.
我在家先把死星的基本框架搭好
I'll knock out the basic bones of the death star at my place.
然后再去找你
I'll come by afterwards.
因为一般情况下 框架是最难拼的
For the most part, the difficult thing is the base of it.
最上面的部分肯定两个小时就能搞定
The top half we can knock out in two hours, tops.
那就这么定了
That'd be great.
我们要迟到了
I'm gonna be late!
好 那么我们要怎么计算
Okay, so how do we calculate
从A点到B点的加速度
linear acceleration between points a and b?
闪电 请讲
Flash.
重力乘上夹角的正弦值
It's the product of sine of the angle
除以质量
and gravity divided by the mass.
回答错误 彼得
Nope. Peter.
你在听课么
You still with us?
在的 在的
Uh, uh, yeah, yeah.
抵消质量 用重力乘上夹角的正弦值就可以了
Mass cancels out, so it's just gravity times sine.
正确 闪电 你看 回答的最快
Right. See, flash, being the fastest
不一定是最好的 因为可能会答错
isn't always the best if you are wrong.
你完蛋了
You're dead.
今天我们来谈谈丹麦物理学家尼尔斯·玻尔
Today we're talking about Danish physicist niels bohr,
相信我 他所提出的量子理论
but trust me, there's nothing bohr-ing
并不是你们想象中的那么无聊
about his discoveries regarding quantum theory.
- 丽兹穿的是新上衣么 - 不
- Did Liz get a new top? - No.
我们以前就见过她就穿过这件的 但是 从来没搭配过那条短裙
We've seen that before, but never with that skirt.
返校舞会快要到啦！你准备好了吗？
- 丽兹 嘿 看起来很不错 - 嗨
- Liz, hey. That looks so good. - Hi!
咱们别一直盯着人家看了 挺诡异的
We should probably stop staring before it gets creepy.
我早就注意到你们两个屌丝啦
Too late. You guys are losers.
那你为啥还坐在那边呢
Well, then why do you sit with us?
因为我没朋友啊
Because I don't have any friends.
下一个问题
Let's move to the next question.
最重的天然元素是什么
What is the heaviest naturally-occurring element?
氢是最轻的
Hydrogen's the lightest.
不对 你问的不是这个
That's not the question. Okay. Yeah.
铀
Uranium.
回答正确 谢谢 亚伯拉罕
That is correct. Thank you, Abraham.
请打开课本 翻到第十页
Yes. Open your books to page 10.
彼得 这可是一次国家级的活动
Peter, it's nationals.
你就请周末两天的假不行么
Is there no way you could take one weekend off?
我不能去华盛顿 因为史塔克先生需要我
I can't go to Washington. If Mr. stark needs me,
我得保证他能在这找到我
I have to make sure I'm here.
你甚至都没见过托尼·史塔克本人
You've never been in the same room as Tony stark.
等等 什么情况
Wait. What's happening?
彼得不去华盛顿了
Peter's not going to Washington.
- 不会吧 - 为什么不去
- No. No, no, no. - Why not?
确定不参加这么重要的活动么
Really? Right before nationals?
你已经退出了行进乐队和机器人小组了
He already quit marching band and robotics lab.
我没有特别关注他 只是善于观察罢了
I'm not obsessed with him. Just very observant.
闪电 你来顶替彼得的位置吧
Flash, you're in for Peter.
噢 我不确定 我得看看我的安排表
I don't know. I gotta check my calendar first.
我和黑寡妇有个约会呢
I got a hot date with black widow coming up.
这是不可能的
That is false.
我是不是说过 那个铃不是用来敲着玩的
What'd I tell you about using the bell for comedic purposes?
- 嘿 哥们 - 嘿
- Hey, what's up? - Hey, man.
德尔马先生 你好
What's up, Mr. delmar?
嘿 帕克
Hey, Mr. Parker.
五号套餐 对吧
Number five, right?
是的 加点泡菜
Yeah, and with pickles,
能不能把它压的扁一点 谢谢
and can you smush it down real flat? Thanks.
没问题
You got it, boss.
你的婶婶过的怎么样
How's your aunt?
她挺好的
Yeah, she's all right.
他婶婶是个很性感的意大利美女
那你女儿呢
- 付钱吧 一共10块 - 明明是5块啊
- Ten dollars. - It's $5.
冲你刚刚说的那句话 你得付10块
For that comment, $10.
嘿 我是开玩笑的
Hey, come on. I'm joking. I'm joking.
给你5块
Here's $5.
你过的怎么样 默夫
What's up, murph?
过的怎么样 伙计
How you doing, buddy?
在学校怎么样
So how's school?
你知道的 还是一样的无聊 我有更重要的事情要做
Ah, you know. It's boring. Got better things to do.
在学校好好学习吧 孩子
Stay in school, kid. Stay in school.
要不然你就要过上我这样的日子了
Otherwise, you're gonna end up like me.
- 你过的挺好的啊 - 给你 这可是皇后区最好吃的三明治
- This is great. - Best sandwiches in queens.
终于有目标了
Finally.
- 抱歉 - 你脑子有问题吧
- Excuse me. - What's the matter with you?
嘿 帮我拿一下这个好么 谢了
Could you hold this for a second? Thanks.
嘿 这是谁的自行车
Hey, is this anybody's bike? No?
- 嘿 伙计 这是你的自行车么 - 我没零钱
- Hey, buddy, is this your bike? - I have no change.
有人带笔了么 能借我支笔么
Does anyone have a pen? Do you have a pen?
这是您的自行车么
如果不是的话  别偷车哟
蜘蛛侠
大家好啊
Everybody good?
嘿
Hey!
嘿 你是网上的那个蜘蛛男 对吧
You're that spider guy on YouTube, right?
叫我蜘蛛侠
Call me spider-man!
好的 蜘蛛侠 来个空翻
Okay, spider-man. Do a flip.
- 耶 - 不错
- Yeah! - Not bad.
嘿 伙计
Hey, buddy.
- 你不该来偷车 这可不太好 - 那是我的车 白痴
- Shouldn't steal cars, it's bad. - It's my car, dumbass!
嘿 把警报声关掉
Hey! Shut that off!
- 能不能麻烦你告诉他 那是我的车 - 我刚刚正试图…
- Can you tell him it's my car? - I was just...
- 喂 我还要上晚班 别闹了 哥们 - 那不是你的车
- yo! I work at nights. Come on. - That's not your car!
- 那是他的车 - 我怎么知道那是他的车
- That's his car. - How was I supposed to know?
- 他干嘛撬车窗呢 - 天天都有这些烦人的警报
- He put that in the window! - Every day with these alarms!
把它关掉 别逼我下去找你的麻烦 你个小混混
Turn it off! Don't make me come down there.
嘿 盖瑞 你过的怎么样
Hey, Gary! How you doing?
玛乔丽 你好啊 你妈妈还好么
Marjorie, how are you? How's your mother?
我没事 我没事
I'm good, I'm good.
这里是哈皮·霍根的
You have reached the voicemail box of:
语音邮箱
Happy hogan.
嘿 哈皮 这是我今晚所做的报告
Hey, happy. Here's my report for tonight.
我阻止了一个自行车大盗
I stopped a grand theft bicycle.
但我找不到失主 所以就留了张字条
Couldn't find the owner, so I just left a note.
嗯…
Um...
我还帮助了一个迷路的老婆婆 她来自多米尼加
I helped this lost, old Dominican lady.
她人很不错 给我买了个油炸饼
She was really nice and bought me a churro.
我感觉我还能做更多的事
I just feel like i could be doing more.
我很好奇 我们的下次任务是什么
You know? Just curious when the next real mission's gonna be.
就这样 记得回我电话
So, yeah, just call me back.
我是彼得·帕克
It's Peter. Parker.
我为什么要跟他说油炸饼的事
Why would I tell him about the churro?
终于可以干点大事了
Finally, something good.
这个高科技武器真是太好用了
Yo, this high-tech stuff makes it too easy.
- 跟你说吧 这个买的不亏 - 快快快
- Told you it was worth it. - Okay, go, go, go.
漂亮
Oh, heh, nice.
我们今晚可以再抢五次了
We can hit, like, five more places tonight.
身份被盗？ 我们来帮您搞定
伙计们 咋回事呢
Ahem. What's up, guys?
忘记取款密码了
You forget your pin number?
你们是复仇者啊
Whoa! You're the avengers.
你们在这干什么呢
What are you guys doing here?
雷神 浩克 终于见到你们俩了
Thor. Hulk. Good to finally meet you guys.
还以为你们本人会更帅气一些呢 钢铁侠
I thought you'd be more handsome in person. Iron man.
你怎么在抢银行呢 你可是百万富翁啊
Hey, what are you doing robbing a bank? You're a billionaire.
我…
Hey...
感觉好奇怪啊
oh, this feels so weird.
那是什么玩意
What is that thing?
我开始觉得 你们不是复仇者了
I'm starting... To think... You're not... The avengers.
911 有什么紧急情况
911. What's your emergency?
蜘蛛侠和复仇者们
Uh, spider-man is fighting the avengers
在21街的银行里打斗
in a bank on 21st street.
伙计们 别闹了 今晚还要上学呢
All right, let's wrap this up. It's a school night.
你们这些混蛋是怎么搞到这种高科技武器的呢
So how do jerks like you get tech like this?
不…
No. Wait, wait, wait! Ah!
德尔马先生
Mr. delmar.
嘿 德尔马先生 你在里面么 里面有人么
Hey, Mr. delmar, you in here? Is anybody in here? Hello?
不是吧
Oh, come on.
我拿着它呢
I gotta...
拿着吧
here, here. Good, yeah.
好 可以 不行
Okay. Good. Yes.
放下这个
Yes... no. No, put that down.
把我们俩给卖了都买不起这个 什么事
That's worth more than you or me. Yeah?
哈皮 刚刚出大事了
Happy, the craziest thing just happeNed to me.
有一伙人在用
These guys were robbing an atm
- 高科技武器抢劫自动取款机 然后… - 嘿 喘口气吧
- with high-tech weapons... - take a breath. I don't have time
我可没时间管什么取款机抢劫犯
for atm robberies yeah, but...
或者是你留下的什么贴心字条
or the notes you leave behind.
我还有搬家的事要操心呢
I have moving day to worry about.
下周前所有东西都要搬走
Everything's gotta be out by next week.
什么 搬家的事 谁要搬家了
Wait, wait. You're moving? Who's moving?
伙计 你从来不看新闻的么
Yeah, don't you watch the news?
托尼把复仇者大厦给卖了
Tony sold avengers tower.
我们要搬到纽约北部一个新的基地去
We're relocating to a new facility upstate
估计那边的手机信号会更差一些
where hopefully the cell service is much worse.
- 那我怎么办 - 什么你怎么办
- But what about me? - What about you?
那如果史塔克先生需要我 或者什么大事发生了 我要怎么办呢
Well, what if Mr. stark needs me or something big goes down?
能不能让我和史塔克先生谈谈
Can I just please talk to Mr. stark?
远离那些太危险的事
Stay away from anything dangerous.
我的责任是 确保你别搞出什么大乱子
I'm responsible for making sure you're responsible, okay?
我是个可靠的人 靠…
I am responsible. I... oh, crap.
- 我的书包不见了 - 你这听起来可不靠谱啊
- My backpack's gone. - That doesn't sound responsible.
- 我回头再打给你 - 要是不打给我就更好了
- I'll call you back. - Feel free not to.
什么情况
What was that?
没什么 没什么
Uh, it's nothing. Nothing.
你就是那个蜘蛛侠
You're the spider-man.
- 网上的那个 - 我不是 我不是
- From YouTube. - I'm not. I'm not.
- 你刚刚还趴在天花板上呢 - 内德 你怎么会在我的房间里呢
- You were on the ceiling. - What are you doing in my room?
你婶婶让我进来的啊 你说过的 我们要一起把死星模型拼完的
May let me in. We were gonna finish the death star.
你不能就这么进我的房间
You can't just bust into my room!
那个火鸡肉卷菜单简直糟透了
That Turkey meatloaf recipe is a disaster.
我们出去吃吧 泰国餐怎么样 内德 你想吃么
Let's go to dinner. Thai? Ned, you want thai?
- 想 - 不 他有点事要忙
- Yes. - No. He's got a thing.
做事之前可以…
A thing to do after.
好吧
Okay.
还是把衣服穿上吧
Maybe put on some clothes.
- 她不知道吧 - 没人知道这事啊
- Oh, she doesn't know? - Nobody knows.
史塔克先生帮我做的装备 就他知道
Mr. stark knows because he made my suit. That's it.
托尼·史塔克给你做的 你加入了复仇者联盟么
Tony stark made you that? Are you an avenger?
基本上 算是吧
Yeah, basically.
你不能告诉别人这事
Oh, geez. You can't tell anybody.
你要保密
You gotta keep it a secret.
- 为什么是个秘密啊 - 如果我婶婶发现
- Secret? Why? - You know what she's like.
我每天都冒着生命危险做事
If she finds out people try and kill me
她肯定不会让我干了啊
every night, she won't let me do this.
求你了 内德
Come on, Ned, please.
好吧 好吧
Okay, okay, okay.
我跟你直说吧
I'll level with you.
我不敢保证我能严守这个秘密
I can't keep this a secret.
这是我听说过的最酷的事啊
It's the greatest thing that's ever happeNed to me.
内德 绝对不能让我婶婶知道 现在还不能告诉她
Ned, may cannot know. I cannot do that to her right now.
你知道吧 她身上
You know? I mean, everything
经历了这么多事 我…求求你了
that's happeNed with her, i... please.
- 好的 - 你要发誓绝不说出去
- Okay. - Just swear it, okay?
我发誓
I swear.
- 谢谢 - 真是难以置信
- Thank you. - Yeah.
我居然还是被人发现了
I can't believe this is happening now.
- 我能试试那个装备么 - 不行
- Can I try the suit on? - No.
它的工作原理是什么 它是不是带磁性 你怎么发射蜘蛛丝的
How's it work? Magnets? How do you shoot the strings?
- 明天去学校再说吧 - 好
- I'm gonna tell you tomorrow. - Great.
好吧 等等…
Okay, well, wait, then.
你是如何同时兼顾这事和在史塔克工业的实习的
How do you do this and the stark internship?
这就是我在史塔克工业的实习内容
This is the stark internship.
快走吧
Just get out of here.
怎么了
What's the matter?
阿斯加德教会
我还以为你喜欢泰餐呢
Thought you loved larb.
是太有泰国特色了么
It's too larby?
还是泰国特色不足
Not larby enough.
我还得跟你说多少句话
How many times do I have to say "larb" before...
你才肯回答我
You talk to me?
你知道的 我很关心你
You know I larb you.
我很焦虑 实习搞得我太累了
I'm just stressed. The internship, and I'm tired.
太多活要干了
A lot of work.
在史塔克工业的实习么
The stark internship.
我跟你说 我个人可不看好托尼·史塔克
I have to tell you, not a fan of that Tony stark.
一直让我心烦意乱 在脑中挥之不去
You're distracted all the time. He's got you in your head.
满脑子都是他...
Delmar's sandwiches destroyed...
他平时让你做什么呢
What does he have you doing?
你要运用你的直觉
You need to use your instincts.
皇后区自助提款机抢劫案
店面受损严重 此前 皇后区的
after an atm robbery was thwarted
罪犯阻止者
by queens' own crime stopper, what?
蜘蛛侠
The spider-man.
试图阻止一伙劫匪抢劫自动取款机 打斗过程中
As the spider-man attempted to foil their heist,
突然出现了一道强力的冲击波
a powerful blast was set off,
直接穿过马路 引发爆炸
slicing through the bodega across the street.
万幸的是 无人受伤
Miraculously, no one was harmed.
要是看到了这样的事
If you spot something like that happening,
你要掉头就跑
you turn and you run the other way.
是的 当然
Yeah. Yeah, yeah, yeah. Of course.
那就发生在离我们六条街的地方
Six blocks away from us.
我要换一个新背包
I need a new backpack.
- 你说什么 - 我要一个新背包
- What? - I need a new backpack.
你都换了五个了
That's five.
- 这是糯米补丁 - 我们没点这个菜
- Sticky rice pudding. - We didn't order that.
这是本店赠送的
It's on the house.
谢谢
Oh. Thanks.
他真是个好人
That's nice of him.
我觉得 他也很关心你
I think he larbs you.
你被蜘蛛咬了一口
You got bit by a spider?
它能咬我一口么
Can it bite me?
应该不会太疼吧
Well, it probably would've hurt, right?
算了 无论疼不疼 我都愿意让它咬我
Whatever. Even if it did hurt, I'd let it bite me.
我不确定 那得有多疼啊
Maybe. How much did it hurt?
那个蜘蛛已经死了 内德
The spider's dead, Ned.
你当时在场
You were here?
是啊
Yeah.
你当时可能会丢命的
You could've died.
你会产卵么
Do you lay eggs?
你这问的…当然不会啊
What? No.
- 你会喷射毒液么 - 不会啊
- Can you spit venom? - No.
你能召集蜘蛛大军么
Can you summon an army of spiders?
不能 内德
No, Ned.
索科维亚协议生效了
The sokovia accords were put into place...
你的网能射多远
How far can you shoot your webs?
不知道 闭嘴吧 别问了
It's unknown. Shut up.
开始监管…
To begin regulating...
如果我是你 我就站在一栋高楼楼顶
If I was you, i would stand on a building
- 用力射出去 看看有多远 - 闭嘴 内德
- and shoot as far as I could... shut up, Ned.
嗨 我是美国队长
Hi. I'm captain America.
无论你是在课堂里 还是在战场上
Whether you're in the classroom or on the battlefield...
- 你也认识他么 - 是啊 我见过他
- Do you know him too? - Yeah, we met.
我偷过他的盾牌
I stole his shield. What?
今天 我的好朋友 你们的体育老师
Today, my good friend, your gym teacher
将会带你们进行 "美国队长体能挑战"
will be conducting the captain America fitness challenge.
谢谢 美国队长
Thank you, captain.
虽然我敢肯定这家伙已经是罪犯了 但我还是得给你们看这视频
Pretty sure he's a war criminal, but I have to show these videos.
这是国家要求的 准备训练吧
It's required by the state. Let's do it.
复仇者们也需要交税么
Do avengers have to pay taxes?
浩克闻起来是啥味道
What does hulk smell like?
- 我敢肯定他闻起来很香 - 内德 闭嘴吧
- I bet he smells nice. - You have to shut up.
美国队长长得帅么 还是他只是个刻薄的老头
Is captain America cool, or is he like a mean, old grandpa?
内德 别问了 行么
Ned, just shh, okay?
嘿 我能不能当你的幕后指挥
Hey, can I be your guy in the chair?
你说什么
What?
你知道的 就是那种 戴个耳机
Yeah. You know how there's a guy with a headset
给手下的人下命令的
telling the other guy where to go?
比如 你被困在了一栋公寓楼里
If you're in a burning building, i could tell you where to go.
我可以告诉你往哪走 因为我前面有一堆电脑屏幕
There'd be screens around me, and I could swivel around.
就是这种幕后指挥
I could be your guy in the chair.
内德 我不需要幕后指挥
Ned, I don't need a guy in the chair.
做的不错 帕克
Looking good, Parker.
要我选的话 我要上了索尔
Now, see, for me, it would be f Thor
嫁给钢铁侠 杀了浩克
marry iron man and kill hulk.
那蜘蛛侠呢
Well, what about the spider-man?
蜘蛛侠只是个小角色啦
It's just spider-man.
你们看到网上的那个监控录像么
See the bank security cam on YouTube?
他一个人解决了4个呢
He fought off four guys.
我的天 她看上蜘蛛侠了
Oh, my god, she's crushing on spider-man.
不是吧
No way.
- 有点吧 - 真恶心
- Kind of. - Oh, gross.
估计他已经30岁了
He's probably, like, 30.
你连他长什么样都不知道
You don't know what he looks like.
如果他以前重度烧伤 全身疤痕呢
What if he's seriously burNed?
我无所谓 我爱的是他的内在
I wouldn't care. I'd love him for the person he is inside.
彼得认识蜘蛛侠
Peter knows spider-man.
我不认识 我…
No, I don't. No. I... I mean...
他们是朋友
they're friends.
是啊 美国队长还是体育老师的朋友呢
Yeah, like coach Wilson and captain America are friends.
我见过他 见过几次 但是…
I've met him, yeah. A couple times.
那是我在
But it's...
史塔克工业实习的时候
Through the stark internship.
嗯 我觉得我们不应该谈这个的
Yeah, well, I'm not really supposed to talk about it.
那真是太酷了
Well, that's awesome. Hey, you know what?
你可以邀请他参加丽兹的派对呢
Maybe you should invite him to Liz's party. Right?
嗯 我今晚要开个派对
Yeah, um, I'm having people over tonight.
非常欢迎你来
You're more than welcome to come.
- 你要开派对 - 是啊 肯定会玩的很嗨
- Having a party? - Yeah, it's gonna be dope.
你可得把你的蜘蛛侠朋友请来了
You should totally invite your personal friend spider-man.
没关系
Um... It's okay.
我知道彼得很忙的 没时间参加派对 所以…
I know Peter's way too busy for parties anyway, so...
不不 他会来的 对吧 帕克
Come on. He'll be there. Right, Parker?
你在搞什么鬼
What are you doing?
我在帮你啊
Helping you out.
你没听到她说的么
Did you not hear her?
丽兹看上你了
Liz has a crush on you.
兄弟 你是个复仇者啊
Dude, you're an avenger.
要说我们中谁最有希望泡到学姐 只有你了
If any one of us has a chance with a senior girl, it's you.
丽兹的家在郊区 我记得的
House party in the suburbs.
我有点嫉妒了
Oh, I remember these. Kind of jealous.
这肯定会是难忘的一夜
It'll be a night to remember. Oh...
内德…一般来说 都是帽子挑人 而你这个 绝对是你挑帽子
Ned, some hats wear men. You wear that hat.
是啊 这顶帽子让我信心十足
Yeah, it gives me confidence. Hm.
这不太妙
This is a mistake.
我们还是回家吧
Hey, let's just go home.
彼得
Oh, Peter.
我明白 对你来说 参加集体活动
I know. I know it's really hard
是件困难的事
trying to fit in with all the changes
你的身体经历了一系列变化
your body's going through.
已经成熟了
It's flowering now.
他最近压力很大
He's so stressed out lately.
参加派对有助于缓解压力
What helps with stress is a party.
所以你应该参加派对
We should go to the party.
行 走吧 走吧
Yeah, let's do it. I'm gonna go.
彼得
Peter...
- 好好玩 - 我会的
- Have fun, okay? - Okay. I will.
再见 梅
Bye, may.
兄弟 装备你带了没
Dude, you have the suit, right?
这简直太刺激了
Yeah. This is gonna change our lives.
安妮 过来啊
Annie, over here!
- 你好 - 你好
- Hey. - Hey.
我叫闪电 我是DJ
Dj flash.
让蜘蛛侠晃进来
Okay. We're gonna have spider-man swing in,
就说你们俩关系很铁
say you guys are tight, and I get
然后我来跟他对上几拳
a fist bump or one of those half bro-hugs.
真不敢相信 你们俩居然来参加派对了
Can't believe you're at this lame party.
你不是也来了么
But you're here too.
是么
Am I?
我的天
Oh, my gosh.
你们好啊 内德 帽子不错
Hey, guys. Cool hat, Ned.
- 你好 丽兹 - 你好 丽兹
- Hi, Liz. - Hi, Liz.
很高兴看到你们来这
I'm so happy you guys came.
这儿有披萨 饮料 随便拿吧
There's pizza and drinks. Help yourself.
- 这派对真不错 - 谢谢夸奖
- What a great party. - Thanks.
我…
Oh, i...
打碎东西 我爸妈会 我得去…
my parents will kill me if anything's broken. I gotta...
- 好的 - 玩的开心
- yeah. - Have fun.
- 拜 - 拜
- Bye. - Bye.
哥们 你愣着干嘛呢
Dude, what are you doing?
她就在这呢 蜘蛛侠变身啊
She's here. Spider it up.
不不不 这样不行
No, no, no. I can't... i cannot do this.
蜘蛛侠可不是什么派对上玩的把戏 我还是
Spider-man is not a party trick, okay?
做我自己就好
Look, I'm just gonna be myself.
彼得 他们想看的不是你啊
Peter, no one wants that.
兄弟
Dude.
你好啊 屁颠儿 帕克
Penis Parker, what's up?
你那个蜘蛛侠哥们在哪呢
So where's your pal spider-man?
让我猜猜 是不是和你幻想中的女朋友在加拿大一起旅游呢
Let me guess: In Canada with your imaginary girlfriend?
你旁边的可不是蜘蛛侠
That's not spider-man.
只是穿着红衣服的内德而已啊
That's just Ned in a red shirt.
嘿 大家好 我是蜘蛛侠
"Hey, what's up? I'm spider-man.
我就是过来和我的哥们彼得打个招呼
"Just thought I'd swing by and say hello to my buddy Peter.
内德 你好啊 彼得在哪呢
"Oh, what's up, Ned? Hey, where's Peter, anyways?
他应该就在附近…
He must be around..."
妈的 这简直太蠢了 我在干什么呢
God, this is stupid. What am I doing?
什么情况
What the hell?
逊爆了
It sucks
这玩意是用从索科维亚回收来的
Now, this is crafted from a reclaimed
次奥创战士手臂 加工制成的
sub-ultron arm straight from sokovia.
给你 来试试
Here. You try.
兄弟 我只想买点低调的武器
Man, I wanted something low-key.
干嘛给我看这种威力大的
Why are you trying to upsell me, man?
好好好 肯定有你看得上眼的东西
Okay, okay. I got what you need, all right?
别急 我这里不错的玩意可多了 等一下
I got tons of great stuff here. One sec.
我这有黑洞手雷 奇塔瑞轨道炮
Okay, I got black hole grenades, chitauri railguns...
你又在公共场合乱开火了 小心点
You letting off shots in public now? Hurry up.
我知道什么适合你 时代不同了
Look, times are changing. We're the only ones
我们是唯一一家出售这些高科技武器的
selling these high-tech weapons.
那些取款机抢劫犯肯定是从这搞到的武器
Oh, this must be where the atm robbers got their stuff.
我只想要点小打小闹的武器
I need something to stick up somebody.
可不想把人一枪打到另外一个时空
I'm not trying to shoot them back in time.
我这还有反重力攀登器
I got antigrav climbers.
你们这还有攀登器
Yo, climbers?
什么情况
Okay, what the hell is that?
- 你给我们下套 - 嘿 兄弟 别急
- Did you set us up? - Hey, hey, man.
嘿 你们想开枪的话 来打我啊
Hey! Come on. You gonna shoot at somebody, shoot at me.
好啊
All right.
那是什么啊
What was that?
什么鬼…
What...?
- 打个电话给他吧 - 不不不
- We gotta call him. - No, no, no, no.
你又用那玩意了
Did you just do it again?
- 闭嘴 - 我要打给他了
- Shut up. - I'm calling him.
我是图姆斯
Toomes's phone.
老大
Boss.
嗷 我的屁股
Oh, my butt!
丫的 看样子我要抄个近路了
Great. Guess I'm gonna have to take a shortcut.
嘿 各位 祝你们玩的开心
Hey, guys. Good game. Have fun.
伙计 抱歉
Hey, hey, buddy.
我没时间陪你玩 去把它捡回来
Sorry, no time to play. Here, go fetch.
闻起来很不错哦
Smells really good.
电影不错
Great movie!
嘿 小女孩们
Oh, hey, guys.
不
No! No!
嘿 我是彼得 给我留言吧
Hey, it's Peter.Leave a message.
彼得 你在哪呢
Peter, where are you?
计划不是这样的 这可不太好啊
The hat's not working. This is not cool.
差点抓到你了
Almost got you.
你还以为能逃出我的手掌心呢
Thought you got away from me, didn't you?
抓到你了
I got you right where I want you.
我来啦
Surprise!
搞什么鬼
What the hell?
嘿
Oh, hey.
然后 他就像个怪物一样俯冲下来
And then he just, like, swooped down like a monster
把我抓住 拖到了
and picked me up, and took me up
一千英尺的高空 再扔下来
like a thousand feet and just dropped me.
你是怎么找到我的 在我的装备上放了追踪器
How'd you find me? Did you put a tracker in my suit?
我给你装的东西可多了
I put everything in your suit.
其中就包括这个加热器
Including this heater.
- 好多了 谢谢 - 你在想什么呢
- That's better. Thanks. - What were you thinking?
那个戴着翅膀的家伙肯定就是这些武器的源头
The guy with wings is the source of the weapons.
我得拿下他
I gotta take him down.
拿下他
Take him down now, huh?
消停点吧 小英雄 会有人来搞定他们的
Crockett, there are people who handle this sort of thing.
- 复仇者么 - 不不不
- The avengers? - No, no, no.
他们拿那么高的工资 可不是干这个的
This is a little below their pay grade.
不管怎么说 史塔克先生 您不用跑这么大老远的
Mr. stark, you didn't have to come out here.
我能搞定的 没事的
I had that. I was fine.
其实 我本人并没有…在这里
Oh, I'm not here.
谢天谢地 这地方还有wifi信号
Thank god this place has Wi-Fi
要不然你就玩完了
or you would be toast right now.
谢谢你 加内什
Thank Ganesh while you're at it.
干杯
Cheers.
听我说 你就别管那个翅膀男了
Look, forget the flying vulture guy, please.
- 为什么 - 为什么
- Why? - Why?
因为我叫你忘了他
Because I said so!
不好意思 我正在教育熊孩子
Sorry, I'm talking to a teenager.
脚踏实地 做点小事情
Stay close to the ground.
帮助一下周围的普通人
Build up your game helping the little people,
比如那个给你买油炸饼的女士
like that lady that bought you the churro.
为什么就不能好好当一个 友善的
Can't you just be a friendly
邻家蜘蛛侠呢
neighborhood spider-man?
但是我已经准备好大展身手了
But I'm ready for more than that now.
不 你并没有
No, you're not. That is not what you thought
- 当我搞定美国队长的时候 你可不是这么说的 - 相信我 孩子
- when I took on captain America. - Trust me, kid.
要他想搞定你 他就能搞定你
If cap wanted to lay you out, he would've.
听我说 如果你再看到
Listen to me. If you come across
这些武器 联系哈皮
these weapons again, call happy.
你在开车吗
Are you driving?
我跟你说 考虑一下读大学的事 越早越好
You know, it's never too early to start thinking about college.
我在麻省理工大学认识些人 通话结束
I got some pull at mit. End call.
不 我不需要读大学 史塔克先生…
No, I don't need to go to...
史塔克先生已经离线
Mr. stark is no longer connected.
我了个去
That's awesome.
脚踏实地 他这是在说什么呢
"Stay close to the ground"? What is he talking about?
老兄 怎么了 我正在回去的路上
Hey, man, what's up? I'm on my way back.
其实我打电话给你 就是想说…
Actually, i was calling to say
你也许不该回来了 听听这个…
maybe you shouldn't come. Listen to this.
当我说"屁颠儿" 你说"帕克"
When I say "penis," you say "Parker."
- 屁颠儿 - 帕克
- Penis! - Parker!
抱歉 帕克 我觉得我们俩还是屌丝
Sorry, Peter.I guess we're still losers.
明天见
I'll see you tomorrow.
明天学校见
I'll see you tomorrow in school.
哇哦
Whoa.
白痴
Idiots.
一群白痴
Idiots!
老大 你老婆一直在给你发短信
Boss? Your wife keeps texting you.
是关于什么刹车灯的事儿
Something about a brake light.
我不是不让你看我手机吗
What'd I tell you about looking at my phone?
抱歉 你忘带手机了
Oh. Sorry. You left it out.
你知道的 我天生好奇心强
You know I'm a curious person by nature.
我已经完成了那个高海拔真空密封的设计
I finished designing that high-altitude vacuum seal.
也许哪天
Huh? In case you want to,
你想干一票大的
you know, go for the big one?
你还在做那个东西 我跟你说过
You're still on that? I told you, no.
别管那个了
The answer's no. Forget it.
我都跟你说过你多少遍了
How many times have I told you
不要在外面开火
not to fire them out in the open?
- 你说过要把东西卖出去啊 - 低调点
- You said, move the merchandise. - Under the radar.
低调点
Under the radar!
这是我们的生存之道
That's how we survive.
如果你引来灾害控制部门的人
If you bring damage control
或者复仇者到这儿 我们就完了
or the avengers down here, we're through.
而你就在外面穿着那个愚蠢的装扮
You're out there wearing that goofy thing,
灯光全开 还称呼自己为 "惊悚"
lighting up cars calling yourself the shocker.
我外表惊悚 我让人们恐惧
"I'm the shocker. I shock people."
这算什么 职业摔跤手么
What is this, pro wrestling?
随你怎么说吧 老顽固
Whatever, old man. Come on.
听着
Look.
我知道你根本不在乎这些
I know you don't give a crap about anything.
但我在乎
But I do.
我干这行
I built this whole place
是因为我要养家糊口
because I got people i have to look after.
是 是 是
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
我告诉你
You know what?
我受不了你这么折腾了
I can't afford your bullshit.
- 你走吧 - 什么
- Get out of here. - What?
你完了 你被开除了
You're done. You're off the crew.
行 我走人
Yeah, all right.
我走人
Heh. All right.
不过我很好奇 你能不能受得了我在外面折腾
Wonder if you can afford me out there, though, right?
这里的事我可一清二楚
With everything I know.
- 你再说一遍 - 我是想说…
- Excuse me? - I'm just saying,
也许你老婆会想知道
maybe your wife would like to know
你的钱是从哪儿来的
where you really get your money from.
- 你知道吗 - 什么
- You know what? - What?
你说对了
You're right.
- 这东西好使吗 - 我不知道
- That work? - I don't know.
我确实受不了
I can't afford that.
等…
W-w-wait.
天啊
Damn.
我还以为这个是反重力枪
I thought this was the antigravity gun.
什么 不 那个才是
What? No, that's that one.
给
Here.
现在你是 "惊悚"
Now you're the shocker.
去把他弄丢的武器找回来
Go out there and find that weapon he lost.
好的
All right.
嘿 多谢你来帮我
Hey, thanks for bailing on me.
嗯 出了点状况
Yeah, well, something came up.
那是什么
Oh, what is that?
我不知道 有人想用这个把我蒸发了
I don't know. Some guy tried to vaporize me with it.
- 真的 - 对
- Seriously? - Yeah.
真酷
Awesome.
怎么会酷 一点都不酷
I mean, not awesome. Totally uncool of that guy.
那些家伙太可怕了
So scary. Yeah.
看 我想这应该是个电源
Well, look, I think it's a power source.
嗯 但它和这些微型处理器都连在一起
Yeah, but it's connected to all these microprocessors.
这是一个感应充电板
That's an inductive charging plate.
我就是用这个来给牙刷充电的
That's what I use to charge my toothbrush.
不管是谁做了这些武器
Whoever's making these weapons
肯定都是利用了外星科技
is combining alien tech with ours.
这简直是人类有史以来最酷的一句话
That is literally the coolest sentence anyone has ever said.
感谢你
I just want to thank you
让我加入这个
for letting me be part of your journey
不可思议的冒险
into this amazing...
小心你的手指不要被刀切到
keep your fingers clear of the blades.
我得弄清楚这是什么并且是谁做的
I gotta figure out what this is and who makes it.
咱们下课后去实验室做些试验
We'll go to the lab after class and run some tests.
开干吧
Let's do it.
首先 我建议我们先测一下发光物的质量
First, we put the glowy thing in the mass spectrometer.
我觉得还是先给 "发光物" 起个名字比较好
We gotta come up with a better name than "glowy thingy."
你说得对
You're right.
糟了
Crap.
过来 过来 快过来
Come on, come on, come on.
高中都把我逼疯了
High schools creep me out.
它这里的味道 你懂我意思吧
They got this funny smell, you know what I mean?
其中一个就是之前试图杀我的人
Hey, that's one of the guys that tried to kill me.
- 什么 - 是的
- What? - Yeah.
我们得赶紧离开这儿
We gotta get out of here.
不不不 我们得跟着他们
No, no, no. I gotta follow them.
也许他们能带我找到把我扔进湖里的人
They can lead me to the guy that dropped me in the lake.
- 有人把你扔进了湖里 - 对啊 那感觉太糟了
- Someone dropped you in a lake? - Yeah, it was not good.
- 彼得 - 待在这儿 内德
- Peter... no. - Stay there, Ned.
彼得
Peter.
你在干嘛呢
What are you doing?
没干嘛
Nothing.
嗯 你呢
Yeah. You good?
在下棋
Chess.
兄弟 你觉得要是老大知道
Man, can you imagine what the boss would say
我们在这里 他会说什么
if he knew where we were?
仪器感应到了一股能量脉冲
It's saying there was an energy pulse here.
这里连个武器的影都没有
There's no sign of the weapon.
就算它之前在这里 现在也不在了
And even if it was here, now it's gone.
我们也走吧
So are we.
这太牛了
This is so awesome.
我知道
I know, right?
现在在布鲁克林
They're in Brooklyn.
斯塔腾岛
Staten island.
正在离开新泽西
Leaving Jersey.
他们不动了
They stopped.
马里兰
Maryland?
- 那儿有什么 - 不知道
- What's there? - I don't know.
邪恶老巢
Evil lair?
- 他们有老巢 - 哥们 一个翅膀男率领的一群人
- They have a lair? - Dude, a gang with alien guns
有外星武器 没错 他们肯定有老巢
run by a guy with wings? Yeah, they have a lair.
够劲爆
Badass.
但是 那地方离这儿至少有300英里远 你打算怎么过去呢
But how are you gonna get there if it's, like, 300 miles away?
那儿离华盛顿很近
It's not too far from D.C.
- 是彼得 - 朋友们
- Hey, it's Peter. - Guys.
- 你怎么来啦 - 大家好
- Peter? - Hey, buddy.
我在想我能不能重新回到队伍里
Yeah, I was hoping I could rejoin the team.
不 没门儿 你不能退出队伍了
No, no way. You can't quit on us,
还指望大家欢迎你回来
stroll up and be welcomed back by everyone.
欢迎回来 彼得
Hey, welcome back, Peter!
闪电 你继续当替补
Flash, you're back to first alternate.
- 什么 - 你的位置现在是他的了
- What? - He's taking your place.
抱歉 咱们是不是可以出发了
Excuse me, can we go already?
因为我希望晚餐前能参加
I was hoping to get in some light protesting
一个在大使馆门前举行的抗议活动 所以…
in front of one of the embassies before dinner.
抗议是爱国的表现 我们上车吧
Protesting is patriotic. Let's get on the bus.
注意了 各位
Focus up, everyone.
下一个主题是土星的卫星
Our next topic is the moons of saturn.
热力学第二定律
Second law of thermodynamics.
- 法兰克·辛纳屈 - 萨普特堡垒
- Frank Sinatra. - Fort sumter.
- 闪电说错了 - 好了 各位 集中注意
- Flash is wrong. - Okay, guys, let's focus.
- 下一题 - 丽兹 别让他们太累了
- Next one. - Liz, don't overwork 'em.
锶 钡 振金
Uh, strontium, barium, vibranium.
很好 彼得 很高兴你能回来
Very good, Peter. Glad to have you back.
我也是
Glad to be back.
…单位的初速电流状态是…
What is the current standard unit of...?
我能接个电话吗 很快就回来
Can I take this real quick? I'll only be a sec.
- 好 没事 - 喂
- Yeah, fine. - Hello?
我这边屏幕发现了点情况 你离开纽约了
Got a blip on my screen here. You left New York?
- 各位 集中注意 - 跟踪器
- Okay, focus up, everyone. - Tracker.
对…只是学校组织的外出活动而已 没什么的
Yeah, it's just a school trip. It's nothing.
哈皮…我必须得说
Look, happy, I gotta say,
你没经过我允许就监视我
you tracking me without permission
这侵犯了我的个人隐私
is a complete violation of my privacy.
- 这不一样 - 什么不一样
- That's different. - What's different?
没什么 这就是一个学术十项全能比赛
Nothing. Look, it's just the academic decathlon.
不是什么大事
It's no big deal. Hey, hey.
是不是大事 我说了算
I'll decide if it's no big deal.
不过听起来确实不是什么大事
Sounds like it's no big deal,
但是记住了 我盯着你呢
but remember, I'm watching you.
- 大家跟紧点不要走散了 - 对
- Everyone stick together. - Yeah.
不是逗我吧 这地方可真大
You kidding me? This place is huge.
- 我见过更大的 - 那里有只鸟
- I've seen bigger. - There's a bird in here.
你带了手提电脑吧
Hey, you brought your laptop, right?
怎么了
Why?
彼得
Peter,
我们为什么要把你装备里的跟踪器取出来
why are we removing the tracker from your suit?
因为我想在那些人再次移动前
Uh, because i gotta follow these guys
顺藤摸瓜找到他们的老大
to their boss before they move again
而且我不想让史塔克先生知道这件事
and I don't really want Mr. stark to know about it.
所以你是在对钢铁侠撒谎
So you're lying to iron man now?
不 我没在撒谎
No, I'm not lying.
他就是不知道我现在有多大的本事
He just doesn't really get what I can do yet.
搞定
Oh, gotcha.
好了 哈皮 祝你追踪台灯愉快
All right, happy, enjoy tracking this lamp.
这里还有许多其他的子系统
There's a ton of other subsystems in here.
但是它们全部被这个 "辅助轮协议" 关闭了
But they're all disabled by the training wheels protocol.
什么
What?
辅助轮协议
"Training wheels protocol"?
关掉它
Turn it off.
我不认为这是个好主意 你瞧…
I don't think that's a good idea.
他们关掉这个是有原因的
They're blocked for a reason.
来吧老兄 我可不需要什么辅助轮
Come on, man, i don't need training wheels.
我受够了 他一直把我当小孩子一样看待
I'm sick of him treating me like a kid all the time.
- 一点都不酷 - 但你确实还是个孩子
- It's not cool. - But you are a kid.
是啊 我可是一个可以徒手拦住公交车的孩子
Yeah, a kid who can stop a bus with his bare hands.
彼得 我就是觉得这个主意不好
Peter, I just don't think this is a great idea.
万一这样是违法的呢
I mean, what if this is illegal?
求求你了
Look, please.
这是一个可以让我证明自己的机会
This is my chance to prove myself.
我能搞定的 内德 拜托
I can handle it. Ned, come on.
我真不觉得这是个好主意
I really don't think this is a good idea.
你可是我的幕后指挥啊
The guy in the chair.
- 别撩我 - 老兄
- Don't do that. - Come on.
那个发光物是重要的证据 一定要保管好 好吗
The glowy thing, it's evidence. Keep it safe, all right?
没问题
Okay. Okay.
- 我走了 - 小心点
- They're moving. - Be careful.
- 嗨 丽兹 - 你来的正好
- Hey, Liz. - Perfect timing.
我们正要去游泳呢
We're gonna go swimming.
快来 快来
Come on, come on. What?
嗨 彼得
Hey, Peter. Hi.
嘿
Hey.
我正要去商业中心复习来着
I was... I was gonna go study in the business center.
彼得 你不需要复习
Peter, you don't need to study.
你是我见过最聪明的人
You're, like, the smartest guy I've ever met.
另外…在比赛前一天
And besides, a rebellious group activity
搞一个叛逆的集体活动对士气有帮助
the day before competition is good for morale.
啊 我也是在TED演讲上看的 所以…
Well, I read that in a Ted talk, so...
我在TED演讲上听到的
i... I heard it in a Ted talk.
还读过一本指导手册
And I read a coaching book.
你真的很看重这次比赛吗
Are you really... this is really important to you.
是的 这事关大家的前程
Yeah. It's our future.
我不想搞砸了
I'm not gonna screw it up.
而且我们刚刚还去搜刮了一些冰箱里的食物
Besides, we raided the minibar
这些糖果只要11块钱
and these candy bars were, like, $11.
所以赶紧收拾一下过来吧
So get your trunks on and come on.
快来啊 快来啊
Come on.
我来啦
Come on. I'm coming, I'm coming.
我们走
Let's go.
晚上好 彼得
Good evening, Peter.
谁在说话
Hello? Hello?
恭喜你通过了
Congratulations on completing
严格的辅助轮协议
the rigorous training wheels protocol
并且获得装备的全部功能
and gaining access to your suit's full capabilities.
啊 谢谢
Ah, thank you.
那么你今晚打算带我去哪
So, where would you like to take me tonight?
我把跟踪器放到一个坏人身上了
I put a tracker on someone. He's a bad guy.
跟踪器已定位
Tracker located.
正在规划路线拦截目标
Plotting course to intercept target.
好的 只要能让我及时赶回
Okay, well, as long as I make it back
十项全能比赛就可以
in time for decathlon, it's fine.
距离目的地还有100米
One hundred meters from destination and closing.
现在跳下去
Jump now.
检测到三个目标
Detecting three individuals.
为什么他们的秘密基地是在加油站
Why is their secret lair
也太寒碜了
in a gas station? That's so lame.
战衣姐姐 他们在干嘛
Hey, suit lady, what are they doing?
你想听到他们的谈话吗
Do you want to hear what they're saying?
我还能听到他们在说什么 当然想
I can hear what they're saying? Uh, yeah.
激活增强性侦查模式
Activating enhanced reconnaissance mode.
我在拉各斯的清理物中找到了一个金属手套
I got the gauntlet from the Lagos cleanup.
- 其余的都是我的 - 哇哦 太酷炫了
- The rest is my design. - Whoa, that's so cool.
不敢相信他们还在清理三曲枝大厦的垃圾
Can't believe they're still cleaning the triskelion mess.
这样最好 他们继续乱作一团
I love it. They keep making messes,
- 咱们闷声发大财 - 目标进站了
- we keep getting rich. - Target inbound.
哇 他们打算抢劫
Whoa, they're in the middle of a heist.
我可以当场抓住他们 棒极了
I could catch 'em all red-handed. This is awesome.
好了 我得再靠近一点
Okay, I'm gonna get a little closer
去看看发生了什么
so I can see what's happening.
你想开启增强性战斗模式吗
Would you like me to engage enhanced combat mode?
"增强性战斗模式" 好啊
"Enhanced combat mode"? Yeah.
启动一击必杀功能
Activating instant kill.
不不不 我不打算杀任何人
No, no, no, no. I don't want to kill anybody.
关闭一击必杀功能
Deactivating instant kill.
你听到了吗
Did you hear that?
刚才发生了什么 那是什么
What the hell just happened? What was that?
你从广告牌上跳下来 脸部着地
You jumped off the sign and landed on your face.
战衣姐姐 我的蛛网发射器是怎么回事
Suit lady, what's wrong with my web-shooters?
快速射击是增强性战斗模式的默认功能
Rapid-fire is the default for enhanced combat mode.
我为什么会需要快速射击
Why would I need rapid-fire?
你想要查看更多的选项吗
Would you like to see more options?
你总共有576种射击组合可供选择
You have 576 possible web-shooter combinations.
史塔克先生用力过猛了
Mr. stark really overdid it.
你们两个在这儿等着
You two wait right here.
等下 你需要打开减震器
Wait. You're gonna want to turn on the dampers
不然你的手臂会被震碎
or that thing will shatter your arm.
减震器在哪
All right, where's the dampers?
- 就选这个了 - 明智的选择
- That one. - Great choice.
你想把它设定为新的默认设置吗
Would you like me to set this as your new default?
- 不不不 - 把它按下去…
- No, no, no. - Push that in.
- 这里吗 - 不是 另一个
- Right here? - No, the other...
不不不 对 按下去
this one here? Yeah, push it.
- 那是什么 - 电击蛛网
- What was that? - Taser webs.
电击蛛网 我不需要电击蛛网
Taser webs? I don't want taser webs.
你看起来对你的蛛网射击设置很不熟悉
You seem to be unfamiliar with your web-shooter settings.
你想要复习一下设置教程吗
Would you like to run a refresher course?
- 不 你给我选吧 - 没问题
- No. Just... you choose. - Sure thing.
6-9-9 你能按时到达吗
Six-Alpha-niner, are you running on time?
收到 指挥中心 6-9-9 尚未超时
Copy, central. Six-Alpha-niner on schedule.
- 发现目标 - 开始行动
- I got a visual. - Green light, green light.
就是他
Oh, that's him.
很好 我看到车队了
Okay. I got eyes on the convoy.
正在靠近目标车辆
Pulling in behind the caboose.
放下固定锚
Deploy anchors.
准备下落
Dropping down.
没有发现危险信号 一切安全
No outgoing distress signals. You're all clear.
看起来他们这儿有不少好东西
Hey. Looks like they got some good stuff here.
真酷
Whoa, cool.
看起来像某种物质相态转换装置
It's like some kind of matter phase shifter.
好了 准备上去
All right, coming up.
嘿 大鸟 这可不是你的东西
Hey, big bird! This doesn't belong to you.
我的天
Oh, god.
- 战衣姐姐 那又是什么 - 你让我来选择的
- Suit lady, what was that? - You told me to choose.
什么 不 把一切恢复正常就好
What? No, just set everything back to normal.
激活全部系统
Activating all systems.
噢 我的头
Oh, my head.
你似乎有轻微的脑震荡
You appear to have a mild concussion.
我这是在什么地方
Hey, so where am i right now?
我不确定
I'm not sure.
集装箱的墙壁屏蔽了我的传感器
The container walls are hindering my sensors.
等一下
Wait a minute.
他们一定是劫持了卡车
They must have hijacked the truck
还带我去了他们的邪恶老巢
and taken me to their evil lair.
好吧战衣姐姐 看来我们这次
Okay, suit lady, we're gonna have to fight
得杀出重围了
our way out of this one.
三 二 一
Three, two, one!
这是什么地方
What is this place?
战衣姐姐 我在哪儿
Suit lady, where am I?
你正在整个
You're in the most secure facility
东海岸最安全的地方
on the eastern seaboard.
灾害控制部门的深度存储库
The damage control deep storage vault.
不是吧 别这样
No. Seriously?
这扇门很可能会一直关到明天早上
The door will most likely remain closed until morning.
明天早上
Morning?
战衣姐姐 我开始觉得
Hey, suit lady, i kind of feel bad
叫你 "战衣姐姐" 是不是不太好
calling you "suit lady," you know?
我应该给你起个名字
I think I should probably give you a name...
比如丽兹 不不不
Like Liz. No, no, no.
算了 这太奇怪了
God, that's... that's weird.
凯伦怎么样
What about Karen?
如果你喜欢的话当然可以叫我凯伦
You can call me Karen if you would like.
凯伦 这个装备还能干什么
Hey, Karen, what else can this suit do?
什么
What?
也许我真该复习一下设置教程
Maybe we should run that refresher course.
- 弹跳网 - 弹跳网
- Ricochet web. - Ricochet web.
真酷 分离网
Whoa! Cool. Splitter web.
- 蛛网手雷 - 蛛网手雷
- Web grenade. - Web grenade!
我该告诉丽兹我就是蜘蛛侠吗
Should I tell Liz that I'm spider-man?
谁是丽兹
Who is Liz?
丽兹是…
Who's Liz? She's... heh.
她是学霸女神
She's the best. She's awesome.
是我的同校同学
She's just a girl who goes to my school.
还有…
And, uh...
我真的很想告诉她
Yeah, I just... i really want to tell her,
但是又感觉很奇葩 你明白我的意思么
but it's kind of weird, you know?
"嘿 我是蜘蛛侠"
"Hey, I'm... I'm spider-man."
这有什么奇葩的
What's weird about that?
如果她期待的蜘蛛侠是像托尼·史塔克那样的呢
What if she's expecting someone like Tony stark?
你想想 她看到是我会有多失望
Imagine how disappointed she'd be when she sees me.
好吧 如果我是她
Well, if I were her,
我一点都不会失望
I wouldn't be disappointed at all.
谢谢 凯伦
Thanks, Karen.
有个人能聊聊天的感觉真好
It's really nice to have somebody to talk to.
我们在这儿待了多久了
Hey, how long we been here anyways?
- 37分钟 - 什么
- Thirty-seven minutes. - What?
才37分钟 这太扯了
Thirty-seven minutes? That's insane.
我受不了了
I cannot take this anymore.
我要离开这儿
I got to... i gotta get out of here.
这里肯定有什么能用得上的
There's got to be something in here I can use.
让我看看
Okay, let's see.
不行
Nope.
这个牛
That's awesome.
嘿 这个看起来很像那个发光物
Ah. Hey, it's like the glowy thing.
这个发光物是一个易爆的奇塔瑞能量核
That glowy thing is an explosive chitauri energy core.
什么 你是说我们一直随身带着一个炸弹
Whoa, whoa! You mean, we've been carrying around a bomb?
它受到辐射才能激活爆炸
It would require radiation to transform it
才能激活爆炸
into an explosive state.
不不不不
No, no, no, no, no.
来人啊 快放我出去
Hey! Please! Please, somebody, let me out! Hey!
凯伦 你必须帮我覆写那个时间锁
Karen, you have to help me override that time lock.
好的凯伦 尝试低压运行
Okay, Karen, lower the voltage and run it.
试验失败
Trial unsuccessful.
好吧 我们要尝试每一个序列
Okay, we're just gonna have to try every sequence.
内德 彼得 我们要迟到了 快点 我们走
Ned, Peter, we're gonna be late. Come on, let's go.
好的 等下 马上就来
Okay. Hold on, hold on.
进行第247次尝试
Initiating trial 247.
成功了 成功了
It worked. It works!
请确保所有手机已关机
Please be sure all cell phones are turNed off.
谢谢
Thank you.
凯伦 快带我回去十项全能比赛 越快越好
Karen, get me to the decathlon as fast as possible.
没问题 告诉我地点
Sure thing. Just tell me where it is.
就在华盛顿纪念碑对面
Across from the Washington monument.
这里是内德的语音信箱 听到请留言
It's Ned. Leave a message.
内德 快回电话 那个发光物是炸弹
Ned, call me back! The glowy thing's a bomb!
你右边有辆顺风车正在接近
There's a vehicle approaching on your right.
我们已经进入了决胜局
We have now entered sudden death.
下一题将决定冠军归属
The next correct answer wins the championship.
中心高中
Midtown tech?
零
Zero.
回答正确
That is correct.
中心高中赢得了本次比赛的冠军
Midtown takes the championship!
- 呜呼 - 我们赢了
- Whoo-hoo! - We won!
各位 我为你们感到骄傲
You guys, i am so proud of you.
跟你们说过 不需要彼得也能赢
Told you we didn't need Peter.
闪电 你一个问题都没有回答
Flash, you didn't answer one question.
米歇尔 你确定不进去吗
Taking it all in? Oh, yeah, I just...
啊 我只是觉得一个出自奴隶之手的东西
um, I don't want to celebrate something
没什么好参观的
that was built by slaves.
噢 我确定华盛顿纪念碑不是由…
I'm sure the Washington monument wasn't built by...
好吧
okay.
- 好好看书吧 - 谢谢
- Enjoy your book. - Thanks.
- 内德 你还活着 - 彼得 你还好吗
- Oh, Ned, you're alive! - Peter, are you okay?
内德 那个发光物在哪
Where's the glowy thing? The glowy thing?
别担心 它很安全 就在我背包里
Don't worry, it's safe. It's in my backpack.
不是的 内德 听好了 那个发光物非常危险
Ned, listen! The glowy thing is dangerous!
你缺席了十项全能比赛 我帮你打掩护了
You missed the decathlon. I covered for you.
- 内德 听我说 - 我们在华盛顿纪念碑 你要怎么…
- Ned, listen to me! - We're at the Washington mon...
- 彼得 是你吗 - 噢 嗨 丽兹
- Peter, is that you? - Hey, Liz.
- 是丽兹吗 - 请让内德接电话
- Is that Liz? - Put Ned on the phone.
- 你应该告诉她你的想法 - 说真的
- Tell her how you feel. - You flake!
你应该庆幸我们赢了
You are so lucky we won.
我很想发火 但我真的很担心你
I want to be mad, but I'm more worried.
你最近是怎么了
Like, what is going on with you?
丽兹 我必须和内德说话 非常重要的事
I have to talk to Ned. It's important!
女士 请把所有物品都放在传送带上
Miss, all items on the belt, please.
丽兹 内德的背包里有非常危险的东西
There's something in Ned's backpack!
不要让它通过X光扫描仪
It's dangerous. Don't let it go through an X-ray.
丽兹 丽兹 糟了
Liz? Liz! Damn it.
哈灵顿先生 能不能由我来告诉彼得他被开除了
Mr. Harrison, can I be the one to tell Peter he's expelled?
华盛顿纪念碑有555英尺
The Washington monument is 555 feet,
5.125英寸高
five and one-eighth inches tall.
由大理石和花岗岩
Notice how the marble and granite
堆砌而成
are cut around the stone.
你听到了那个声音么
Did you hear that?
不不不 凯伦 上面发生了什么
No, no, no. Karen, what's going on up there?
奇塔瑞能量核被引爆了
The chitauri core has detonated
并且对电梯造成了严重的结构损坏
and caused severe structural damage to the elevator.
分析中
- 我的朋友在上面 - 什么
- Oh, no. - My friends are up there.
啊 别担心女士 不会有事的
What? Don't worry, ma'am, everything's gonna be okay.
让一下 让一下 不是吧 这么高
Excuse me, excuse me. Oh, my god, that's tall.
我的天啊 快看天花板
Oh, my god. Look at the ceiling.
大家请保持冷静
Just stay calm, everyone.
我们要死在这里了
Oh, we are all going to die here.
预计10分钟后发生灾难性事故
Estimating 10 minutes before catastrophic failure.
我们完蛋了
We're freakin' screwed.
好了 各位 我知道这看上去很可怕
Okay, I know that was scary,
但我们的安全系统还在运行
but our safety systems are working.
安全系统已经彻底失灵
The safety systems are completely failing.
我们在这里会很安全
We're very safe in here.
电梯里的人正面临生命危险
The occupants are in imminent mortal danger.
我已经尽可能快了
I'm going as fast as I can!
快 把手给我
Let's go. Give me your hand.
预计125秒后发生灾难性事故
You now have 125 seconds until catastrophic failure.
- 什么 为什么 - 预料之外的位移
- What? Why? - Unexpected motion has caused
警告
导致情况加速恶化
the deterioration to escalate.
我该怎么进去
How do I get in there?
激活侦察无人机
Activating reconnaissance drone.
哇哦 这东西一直都在这里吗 太酷炫了
Whoa. Has that been there this whole time? That's awesome.
寻找最佳入口点
Locating optimal entry point.
前往西南窗口
Proceed to southwest window.
我这就去
Karen, I'm on my way.
天啊天啊 好吧
There's a lot of glass here. You got this.
继续爬
Keep coming, keep coming.
我的天
Ah!
Okay. Oh, my god.
我的天
Okay.
怎么了 你已经到了西南窗口
What's wrong? You've reached the southwest window.
- 为什么犹豫了 - 我没事
- Why are you hesitating? - It's fine.
只是从来没到过这么高的地方
I've just never been this high before.
你没有重新装置降落伞
You have also not reinstalled your parachute,
从这个高度跌落是致命的
so a fall from this height would most likely be lethal.
好吧
Perfect.
我的天
Oh, my god.
怎么踢不碎
Why is it not breaking?
这是四英寸厚的防弹玻璃
It's four-inch ballistic glass.
你需要更强的力量
You'll have to create more momentum.
我们是大都会警察 请亮明身份
This is D.C. Metro police.
我的朋友在里面 快停下
Identify yourself. My friends are in there! Stop!
请立刻回到地面
Return to the ground immediately.
- 好了 谁是下一个 - 我 该我了
- Okay, who's next? - Me, it's my turn!
闪电 你在干嘛
Flash, seriously? What are you doing?
别管奖杯了
Come on. Don't worry about the trophy.
退后
Stand down!
马上回到地面
Return to the ground immediately!
回到地面 否则我们开火了
Return to the ground or we will open fire!
往上 往上
Go up, go up.
我能行的
I got this.
拿好我的奖杯
Take my trophy!
这是你最后的机会
This is your last chance!
我感觉要死了
Oh, I'm gonna die.
小心
Look out!
我做到了
I did it! Whoa!
呃哼 大家还好么
Ahem. Hey, how you doing?
嗨 大家怎么样 别担心 我能搞定
Don't worry about it. I got you.
- 太好了 太好了 - 嘿嘿嘿嘿
- Yes! Yes! - Hey, hey, hey.
- 大胖子 别乱动 - 不好意思 不好意思
- Big guy, quit moving around. - I'm sorry, sir. So sorry.
快
Let's go, let's go!
好了 好了
Okay, okay.
- 哈灵顿先生 快走 - 内德 快走
- Mr. harrington, go. - Ned, come on.
该你了 快点 丽兹
This is your stop. Come on, Liz.
动作快点 所有人都出去
Go, go, go. Everybody out!
快走快走
Move it, people. Move it, move it!
- 你确定这样安全么 - 丽兹
- Are you sure it's safe? - Liz!
没事了 你没事了
You're okay. You're okay.
没事了
Okay.
- 我的天 - 太好了
- Oh, my god. - Good, good.
快快 各位靠后点
Come on up. Come on, you guys, stay back.
- 我抓住你了 - 大家都没事吧
- Come on in. - You guys good?
大家都没事了吧
So is everyone okay?
彼得 你的机会来了
This is your chance, Peter.
吻她
Kiss her.
谢谢你
Thank you.
你真的是彼得·帕克的朋友吗
Are you really friends with Peter Parker?
我能完成下笔订单
I can finish the next order,
但如果没有了卡车上的新材料的话…
but without any new materials from that truck...
该死的
Yeah, damn it.
我们至少还能继续做加根的那笔交易吧
We still have enough to do the gargan deal though, right?
对 不过就到此为止了
Yeah, but then that's it.
也许是时候完成那个高空密封装置了
Oh, maybe it is time that i built the high-altitude seal.
- 不要再提那个了 - 可是 差一点…
- Would you shut up about that? - It's only one job.
不行
No.
8年了 联调局没找上门
Eight years, not a word from the feds,
史塔克大楼里的那帮万圣节装扮的
nothing from those Halloween-costume-wearing bozos
复仇者们也没找上门
up there in stark tower.
然后突然就冒出来了一个
And then all of a sudden,
穿着红色紧身裤的小混蛋…
this little bastard in red tights shows up
以为能摧毁我亲手建立起来的一切
and he thinks he can tear down everything I've built.
可能么
Really?
我得找到他
I'm gonna kill him.
- 然后杀了他 - 找到他了
- I'm gonna find him... i found him.
蜘蛛侠突然出现 拯救了一只来自
Spider-man swooped in, heroically saving
皇后区的学术十项全能比赛队伍
an academic decathlon team from queens.
蒙面英雄的身份仍未揭开
The identity of the masked hero is still unknown.
蜘蛛侠爬上华盛顿纪念碑
妈妈
Mom. Okay. All right.
彼得 快过来
Peter? Come here, come here.
我的天
Oh, my god.
中心高中的学术十项全能队伍上周末
This past weekend, midtown's academic decathlon team
击败了全国最强的几支队伍
defeated the country's best
赢得了全国冠军
to win the national championship.
在这之后又击败了死神
Later that day, they also defeated death.
各种爆炸 萨莉在叫 闪电在叫 所有人都在叫
Explosion. Sally scream. Flash scream. All scream.
到处都是紫色的激光和烟雾
There were purple lasers and smoke everywhere.
大家挤作一团就像邦乔维的演唱会一样
It was tight, like a bon jovi concert.
没错 我们活下来了
As you know, we made it out alive,
这才是最重要的
and that's the important thing.
我无法忍受在学校旅行中失去任何一名学生
I couldn't bear to lose a student on a school trip.
再也不要了
Not again.
谢天谢地 没有人受伤
Thankfully, no one was seriously injured,
多亏了蜘蛛侠
thanks to the spider-man.
谢谢你 蜘蛛侠
Thank you, spider-man. Thank you, spider-man.
蜘蛛侠热潮正在席卷校园
Up next: The spider-man mania is sweeping the school.
你会如何展现你的蜘蛛精神
How can you show your spider spirit?
哥们儿 哥们儿
Dude, dude, dude, dude, dude.
名声大噪又无人知晓你的真实身份 你感觉如何
What is it like being famous when nobody knows it's you?
太爽了 内德 太爽了
Crazy, dude. It's crazy.
- 我们应该告诉大家是你吗 - 不
- Should we tell everyone? - No.
我应该告诉大家是你吗
Should I tell everyone?
不 哥们儿 这不是个好主意
No, dude. That's not a good idea.
好了 我们得去上课了
Okay, come on, we'll be late to class.
- 我不去上课 - 你因为缺席十项全能比赛
- I'm not going to class. - You're already in trouble
- 已经惹了很多麻烦了… - 哥们儿 听着 我已经搞清楚了
- for ditching the decathlon. - Dude, listen, I figured it out.
那个翅膀男正在偷
The wingsuit guy is stealing from damage control.
灾害控制部门的材料
What he takes from damage control,
用来制造武器
that's how he builds the weapons.
我现在只要抓到他就行了
So all I gotta do is catch him.
但是我们还有一个西班牙语测试
But we have a Spanish quiz.
内德 我很可能不会再回来上课了
Ned, I'm probably never gonna come back here.
史塔克先生把复仇者基地搬到纽约北部了 所以…
Mr. stark is moving the avengers upstate
- 如果我带着这个翅膀男过去… - 伙计
- so when I bring this guy in... - dude.
你想成为一名高中肄业生吗
You want to be a high school dropout?
我已经不止是一名高中生了
I am so far beyond high school right now.
帕克 来我办公室一趟
Parker, my office.
那么
So...
你被留堂了
You got detention.
你搞砸了 你知道你错了
You screwed up. You know what you did was wrong.
问题是 你该怎么弥补
The question is, how are you gonna make things right?
你可能想变得很酷
Maybe you were trying to be cool.
但是听听我这个被冷冻了65年的老家伙的建议吧
But take it from a guy who's been frozen for 65 years,
想要变酷的唯一方法就是遵守规矩
the only way to really be cool is to follow the rules.
我们都知道什么是对的什么是错的
We all know what's right. We all know what's wrong.
下次再有蠢货想教唆你去…
Next time those turkeys try to convince you of something
你去哪儿 回来
you know is wrong... Where you going? Get back here.
美国队长会怎么做
Just think to yourself, what would captain America do?
你怎么在这儿 你又没有被留堂
Why are you here? You don't even have detention.
哦 我知道 我就是在这
Oh, I know. I just like coming here
素描危机人物的画像
to sketch people in crisis.
这个是你
Heh. It's you.
所以你的身体在发生变化
So your body's changing.
相信我 我知道那是什么感觉
Believe me, I know how that feels.
梅
May?
嗨 凯伦 你在吗
Hey, Karen. What's up?
嗨 彼得 你的西班牙语测试怎么样了
Hey, Peter.How was your Spanish quiz?
那个 我想你或许可以帮我
I was wondering if you could help me.
我想知道那天晚上桥下的
I'm trying to figure out who the guys
那些家伙是谁
under the bridge were that night,
我只记住了部分车牌号
but I can only remember part of a license plate.
我可以对那段录像
I can run facial recognition
进行面部识别
on the footage of that encounter.
- 录像 - 是的 彼得
- Footage? - Yes, Peter.
我可以记录你看到的一切
I record everything you see.
- 每时每刻都记录了吗 - 是的
- Everything? Like, all the time? - Everything.
它叫做婴儿监护协议
It's called the baby-monitor protocol.
好吧 当然了
Yeah, of course it is.
嗯 看一下上周五的录像
Um, yeah, just roll it back to last Friday.
没问题
With pleasure.
嗨 大家好 很不错的聚会
Hey, everyone. Yeah, kick-ass party.
你好啊 丽兹 彼得经常跟我提起你
What's up, Liz? Peter's told me a lot about you.
不不 这只是我在瞎胡闹而已
No, no, no. This is just me messing around.
播放那天晚些时候的…
Go later in the day, later in the day.
这就是我 索尔 奥丁之子
It is I, Thor, son of Odin!
不不不 这显然不是
No, no, no. That's definitely...
我们想看的
that's not what we wanted to watch.
你真是非常有趣
Your impressions are very funny.
快进到武器交易的时候
Fast-forward to the arms deal.
好了
Okay.
右边的两个是谁
The two on the right, who are they?
正在搜索执法机构数据库…
Searching law enforcement databases.
没有找到这两个人的任何记录
No records found for two of the individuals.
- 没有 - 已识别一人
- Nothing? - One individual identified.
安龙·戴维斯 33岁
Aaron Davis, age 33.
有前科 并且就住在皇后区
He has a criminal record and an address here in queens.
那我们去拜访一下他吧
Let's pay him a visit.
你想要激活
Would you like me to activate
增强性审讯模式吗
the enhanced interrogation protocol?
好啊
Uh, yeah.
还记得我吗
Remember me? Hey...
我要问你一些话 你要马上回答我
I need information. You'll give it to me now.
- 好吧 冷静… - 快点
- All right, chill. - Come on!
- 你的声音怎么了 - 你什么意思
- What happeNed to your voice? - What do you mean?
那天在桥下我听过你的声音 很像个女孩
I heard you by the bridge. I know what a girl sound like.
我不是女孩 我是男孩
I'm not a girl! I'm a boy.
我是说 我是个男人
I mean, I'm a... I'm a man.
我不管你是男孩还是女孩…
I don't care what you are, a boy, a girl...
我不是女孩 我是个男人
I'm not a girl! I'm a man.
兄弟
Come on, man.
快告诉我是谁在出售那些武器
Look, who is selling these weapons?
给我提供些名字 或者其他信息
I need to know. Give me names or else.
你第一次干这事儿吧
You ain't ever done this before, huh?
关闭增强性审讯模式
Deactivate interrogation mode.
哥们
Look, man,
那些人出售的武器非常危险
these guys are selling weapons that are crazy dangerous.
不能让他们这么逍遥法外
They can't be out on the streets.
如果一个武器就能把德尔马先生的店切成两半…
If one of them can cut delmar's bodega in half...
- 你知道德尔马 - 对啊 皇后区最好的三明治
- You know delmar's? - Yeah, best sandwich in queens.
- 天堂街的更好 - 啊 就是面包太多了点
- Sub haven's pretty good. - It's too much bread.
- 我喜欢面包 - 哥们 求你了
- I like bread. - Come on, man, please.
白痴一样的审讯模式 凯伦 以后别再激活了
Stupid interrogation mode. Karen, don't ever do that again.
那天晚上你对那家伙说
The other night, you told that dude,
"要开枪就冲我来"
"if you shoot somebody, shoot me."
真的挺有种的
It's pretty ballsy.
我也不想那些武器出现在皇后区
I don't want those weapons in this neighborhood.
我外甥也住在这儿
I got a nephew who live here.
那些人是谁
Who are these guys?
你有关于翅膀男的消息吗
What can you tell me about the guy with the wings?
只知道他是一个疯子 穿着像恶魔一样 除此以外 就没了
Other than he's a psychopath dressed like a demon, nothing.
我不知道他是谁 也不知道他在哪
I don't know who he is or where he is.
- 但我知道他会去哪儿 - 真的吗
- I do know where he's gonna be. - Really?
对 我以前和一个很疯狂的家伙合作过
Yeah, this crazy dude i used to work with,
他应该在和翅膀男做交易
he's supposed to be doing a deal with him.
好的 太棒了
Yes! Heh. Yes.
- 谢… - 等下
- Thank.. - Hey. Hey. Hey.
我都没有告诉你在哪 你怎么去
I didn't tell you where. You don't have a location.
对 就是 我的错 我犯傻了
Right, of course. Yeah, my bad. Silly. Just...
那么
yeah.
- 他在哪 - 我能给你点建议吗
- Where is it? - Can I give you some advice?
你这方面的工作
Hm? You got to get better
- 有待加强 - 不懂你的意思
- at this part of the job. - I don't understand.
我已经很有威慑力了
I'm intimidating.
- 斯塔腾岛渡口 11点 - 哦 那很快了
- Staten island ferry, 11. - Oh, that's soon.
那个两小时后就自动溶解了
Hey, that's gonna dissolve in two hours.
不不不 帮我解开
No, no, no, no. Come fix this.
- 两小时 你罪有应得 - 我还有冰激凌要吃呢 伙计
- Two hours. You deserve that. - I got ice cream in here.
你是个罪犯 你罪有应得 再见了 罪犯先生
You deserve that. You're a criminal. Bye, Mr. criminal.
漂亮
Nice.
凯伦 激活增强性侦查模式
Okay, Karen, activate enhanced reconnaissance mode.
没问题
Sure thing.
他就在前面 主甲板
He's up front, main deck.
我讨厌这家伙
I hate this guy.
这就是桥下的那个对吗
It's the guy from the bridge, right?
- 另一个是谁 - 继续保持联络
- Who's that other guy? - Just keep me posted.
犯罪数据库中没有任何关于他的记录
There's no record of him in my criminal database.
有一通来自梅·帕克的电话
Incoming call from may Parker.
需要我转接到你的显示器上吗
Should I reroute to your heads-up display?
现在没法接 我待会儿再打给她
I can't talk right now. I'll call her back.
小蜘蛛 帮我盯着那家伙
Hey, dronie, keep an eye on that guy.
这回不能放跑任何人了
We can't let anybody get away this time.
- 左边的人是谁 - 麦克·加根
- Who's the guy on the left? - Mac gargan.
前科累累的杀人犯
Extensive criminal record, including homicide.
是否需要激活一击必杀功能
Would you like me to activate instant kill?
不 凯伦 别再提什么一击必杀了
No, Karen, stop it with the instant kill already.
白色小货车
White pickup truck.
小蜘蛛 扫描整艘船 找到那辆白色小火车
Dronie, scan the ship for a white pickup truck.
太好了
Oh, this is too perfect.
武器买家卖家都齐了
They got the weapons, buyers and sellers in one place.
- 托尼·史塔克来电 - 不不不 不接
- Incoming call from Tony stark. - No, no, no.
- 别接 - 帕克先生 有空聊聊么
- Don't answer. - Mr. Parker. Got a sec?
- 我在学校呢 - 你没在学校
- Uh, I'm actually at school. - No, you're not.
华盛顿的事干得漂亮啊……
Nice work in D.C. okay.
我老爸从来没有给我很多帮助
My dad never really gave me a lot of support
我现在要打破这个恶性循环…
and I'm trying to break the cycle of shame.
我现在有点忙……
I'm kind of in the middle of something.
我夸你的时候你不要打断我
Don't cut me off when I'm complimenting you.
总之 好事要发生了…那是什么声音
Anyway, great things are about to... what is that?
我在乐队训练…
I'm at band practice.
奇怪 哈皮跟我说你6周前就退出乐队了
That's odd. Happy told me you quit band six weeks ago.
- 怎么了 - 我要走了
- What's up? - I gotta go!
结束通话
End call. Hey.
这个归我了
I'll take those!
喂 各位 非法武器交易渡船是10 30那班
Hey, guys. The illegal weapons-deal ferry was at 10:30.
你们错过了
You missed it!
蜘蛛男出现了
Spider guy is here.
喂喂喂 别那么着急
Whoa, whoa, whoa! Not so fast.
你们还好吧 我错了 太用力了
Are you guys okay? My bad. That was a little hard.
要我说 之前另一个人更擅长用这武器
I got to say, the other guy was way better with that thing.
说实话
I'm honestly...
把我吓到了
I'm... I'm shocked.
别动 FBI
Freeze! FBI! Don't move!
趴在地上
Get on the ground! FBI!
- 什么 FBI - FBI就是联邦调查局…
- What do you mean, FBI? - The federal bureau of invest...
我知道FBI是什么 但是他们来这里干嘛
I know what "FBI" means. But what are they doing here?
搞什么…
What the...?
快让开 快让开
Get out of the way! Get out of the way!
小心 小心
Go, go, go, go!
快闪开 快闪开 快闪开
Get out of there! Whoa!
小心点 小心点 让开
Look out! Look out! Move! Move! Move!
- 快走 - 去顶层夹板
- Move! - Get to the top deck.
我们离开这里
We're getting out of here.
激活脉冲蛛网
Activate taser web!
你都不知道你在瞎搞什么
You're messing with things you don't understand.
我的天啊 我该怎么办
Oh, my god. What do I do?
凯伦 帮我扫描船身的
Karen, give me an X-ray of the boat
所有承重点
and target all the strongest points.
蛛网手榴弹 蛛网手榴弹
Web grenade. Web grenade.
分散网
Splitter web, go.
干得好 彼得 你已经成功了98%
Great job, Peter.You are 98 percent successful.
- 98 - 干得好 蜘蛛侠
- Ninety-eight? - Yeah, spider-man!
不不不
No, no, no. No!
不
No!
我的天
Oh, my god!
What the hell?
什么情况
你好啊 蜘蛛侠…
Hi, spider-man.
不是说 "乐队训练" 么
Band practice, was it?
看天上
Look! Look!
干得好 钢铁侠
Yeah, iron man!
史塔克先生
Uh, Mr. stark.
史塔克先生 我能做点什么
Hey, Mr. stark, could I do anything?
你想让我做些什么
What do you want me to do? Whoa!
我觉得你已经做得够多了
I think you've done enough.
就这样了 你要跑路了
So that's it? You're just gonna run?
FBI的人盯上我们了
Feds were waiting for us.
现在 钢铁侠也盯上我们了
Now we're on iron man's radar?
是啊 我要跑路了
Yeah, I'm running.
你也应该开溜了
You should too.
你知道我不能这么一走了之
You know i can't do that.
那现在怎么办
So now what?
梅森 你的那个高海拔真空密封的玩意
Mason, can you get that high-altitude
能及时做出来吗
seal thing up and running in time?
你是认真的么
Seriously?
当然可以 包你满意
Yes. You will not regret this.
你加入吗
You in?
你上次搞砸的时候
Previously on Peter screws the pooch,
我叫你别管这事
I tell you to stay away from this.
然而 你为了掩盖行踪
Instead, you hacked a multimillion-dollar suit
黑掉了价值百万美金的装备
so you could sneak around behind my back
背着我 做那些我让你别做的事
doing the one thing I told you not to do.
大家都没事吧
Is everyone okay?
都是你干的好事
No thanks to you.
都是我干的好事
No thanks to me?
有人在外面贩卖那些武器
Those weapons were out there
我一直跟你讲
and I tried to tell you about it,
你就是不听
but you didn't listen.
你要是听我的
None of this would've happeNed
这些都不会发生
if you had just listeNed to me.
你要是真的在乎 你本人就会来这
If you even cared, you'd actually be here.
我听了 小子
I did listen, kid.
你以为是谁叫的FBI
Who do you think called the FBI, huh?
你知不知道 我是唯一信任你的人
Do you know I was the only one who believed in you?
其他人都说我真是疯了
Everyone else said I was crazy
- 居然招一个14岁的小孩 - 我15了
- to recruit a 14-year-old kid. - I'm 15.
闭嘴 大人在说话
No. This is where you zip it, all right?
别插嘴
The adult is talking.
今晚要是有人死了怎么办
What if somebody had died tonight?
那性质就完全不同了 对吧 都是因为你
Different story, right? 'Cause that's on you.
要是你死了
And if you died,
我就觉得是我的责任了
I feel like that's on me.
我不想良心受谴责
I don't need that on my conscience.
是的 先生 对不起我…
Yes, sir, I'm sorry. Yes.
- 我明白 - 对不起是没用的
- I understand. - Sorry doesn't cut it.
我只是想要和你一样
I just wanted to be like you.
但我希望你能更好
And I wanted you to be better.
好吧 说这些都没用
Okay, it's not working out.
我要把装备收回来
I'm gonna need the suit back.
- 收回多久 - 永远
- For how long? - Forever.
- 只有这样才能治你 - 不不不不 别…
- Yeah, that's how it works. - No, no. Please. Please.
- 给我吧 - 你不明白…
- Let's have it. - You don't understand.
我只有这套装备了 没了它我什么都不是
This is all I have. I'm nothing without this suit.
如果没了它 你什么也不是
If you're nothing without this suit,
那你就不配有它 懂了吗
then you shouldn't have it, okay?
天哪 我跟我爸当年的口气一模一样
God, I sound like my dad.
我没其他衣服了
I don't have any other clothes.
好 我们想办法解决
Okay, we'll sort that out.
嘿
Hey.
我一整天都在打你电话
I've been calling you all day.
但你没接
You didn't answer your phone.
你不能这样
You can't do that.
然后又出了渡船的事…
Then this ferry thing happens.
我给5个警局打了电话
I've called five police stations.
5个 我给5个你的朋友打了电话
Five. I called five of your friends.
- 我给内德的妈妈打了电话 - 我没事 梅 我没事
- I called Ned's mother. - I'm fine. May, I'm okay.
真的 放松点 我没事
Honestly, just relax. I'm fine.
少废话 我知道你留堂了
Cut the bullshit. I know you left detention.
我知道你在华盛顿的时候离开了酒店房间
I know you left the hotel room in Washington.
我知道你每晚都溜出房间
I know you sneak out of this house every night.
这一点都不好
That's not fine.
彼得 你要告诉我到底怎么回事
Peter, you have to tell me what's going on.
说吧 我保证不说出去
Just lay it out. It's just me and you.
我失去了史塔克工业的实习机会
I lost the stark internship.
- 什么 - 是的
- What? - Yeah.
怎么回事
What happened?
我以为只要我努力工作 他就可以…
I just thought that i could work really hard
他就会…
and he could... he would... you know.
但是…我搞砸了
But... I screwed it up.
没事 没事的
Oh, it's okay, it's okay.
没事…
It's okay.
不好意思让你担心了
I'm sorry i made you worry.
我知道我不想毁了你的生活
You know I'm not trying to ruin your life.
是的 我知道
Yeah, I know.
我以前…
Just...
我过去也溜出去过
I used to sneak out too. Yeah.
去洗个澡
And take a shower. You smell.
你闻起来好像垃圾一样
You smell like... you smell like garbage.
知道了
I know.
彼得 你是个好孩子 你是个聪明的孩子
Peter, you're a good kid and you're a smart kid,
所以 保持头脑清醒 好不好
so just try to keep your head straight, okay?
好
Okay.
好吧 出去吧
All right, get out of here.
你被开除了吗
Are you expelled?
你要去46街的那个高中吗
Do you have to go to that school on 46th
那个高中的校长有一个十字弓
where their principal has a crossbow?
我很肯定那是传说
Pretty sure that's an urban myth,
而且我还没被开除
and, no, I'm not expelled.
你可真幸运啊
You're so lucky.
我很好 帕克先生(西班牙语)
Muy bueno, se? or Parker.
嘿
Hey.
你好…我以为你在上第五节的微积分课呢
I thought you had calculus fifth period.
我刚在搞返校会的事
Yeah, I was just doing some homecoming stuff.
嗯 听着 我…
Hey, look, i...
关于学术比赛的事
I just wanted to apologize
我想跟你道个歉
about the whole decathlon thing.
没事啦
It's fine.
上周 学术比赛是最重要的事 但是…
Last week, decathlon was the most important thing,
我差点死了
but then i almost died.
不 我只是…
No, I just... I'm...
我就是想说…
I just mean that
这一点都不好 特别是…
it was not cool, especially...
因为…
Because...
我喜欢你
I like you.
我知道
I know.
你知道
You do?
你可真不会保密啊
You're terrible at keeping secrets.
是啊 你该很吃惊吧
Yeah, you'd be surprised.
我要去上课了 但是…
I got to get to class, but...
我们该出去玩一玩
I'd say we should hang out,
但是我要被留校一会儿…
but I'm gonna be in detention for...
但是…
Uh-huh. Ever, but...
我猜你已经有返校节的约会对象了
I guess you already have a date to homecoming.
事实是 我一直忙着策划
Actually, I was so busy planning it,
还没来得及想找约会对象 所以…
I never really got around to that part, so...
你想和我
Uh, you want to
一起去吗
go with me?
好呀
Yeah. Sure.
真的 我的意思是…好啊 太好了
Really? I mean, great. Cool.
太好了
Cool.
我要走那边
I'm actually going that way.
梅 我需要你的帮助
May, I need your help.
怎么样
Right?
好戏登场 你有什么打算
It's game day.So what's the plan?
给她开车门
Open the door for her. Mm-hm.
告诉她 她很漂亮 但是不能太夸张了
Tell her she looks nice, but not too much
否则听起来很奇怪 还有…
because that's creepy. Don't be creepy.
和她跳舞的时候
No. And when I dance with her,
我会把手放在她的屁股上
I'm putting my hands on her hips. I got this.
爱你 拜拜
Love you. Bye.
你就是彼得吧
You must be Peter.
是的
Yeah.
我是丽兹的爸爸
I'm Liz's dad.
东西放那吧
Put 'er there.
手劲不小啊
Hell of a grip.
进来 进来
Come on in here. Come on.
你好 彼得
Hi, Peter.
你看起来好帅啊
You look very handsome.
谢谢
Thank you.
你记住他的名字了吧
You got his name right?
弗莱迪 彼得
Freddie? Peter.
彼得 彼得
Peter. Peter.
我去叫丽兹
I'm gonna go get Liz.
好
Okay.
你没事吧 彼得
You all right, Pete?
没事
Yeah.
你看起来脸色很苍白啊
Because you look pale.
你要喝点东西吗
You want something to drink?
比如波旁威士忌
Like a bourbon
苏格兰威士忌之类的
or a scotch, or something like that?
我还没到喝酒的年龄呢
I'm not old enough to drink.
回答满分
That's the right answer.
哇 你看起来好美啊
do you look beautiful.
老爸 不要让我出糗
Please don't embarrass me, dad.
她是不是很美 彼得
Doesn't she, Pete?
你看起来真漂亮
Yeah, you look really good.
又是个满分回答
Once again, that's the right answer.
那是小花束吗
Is that a corsage?
谢谢
Thanks.
我是你们的司机
Well, hey, I'm your chauffeur,
我开车送你们过去
so let's get this show on the road.
等下 我们要
No, no, no, we have to take
拍照 宝贝
some pictures, babe. All right.
在这 完美…
Oh, right here. Perfect. Mom.
来吧
Okay. Come on, you guys.
彼得 靠近点
Peter, closer.
笑一个
Smile.
拍好啦
There you go.
先生 您不用送我们去的
Sir, you don't have to drive us.
小事一桩
Nah, nah, it's not a big deal.
我要出城 顺路呢
I'm going out of town. It's right on my way.
他总是东奔西跑的
He's always coming and going.
最后一次啦 宝贝
Last time. Have fun.
谢谢 我保证
Thank you. Promise.
他挺不错的
He's cute. Shh.
过几天见
See you in a couple of days.
亲爱的 再见 再见
Bye, baby. All right.
走吧 佩德罗
Come on, Pedro.
拜拜 彼得 玩得开心 好的 我会的
Bye, Peter. Have fun. Yeah, I will.
你打算做啥 彼得
What are you gonna do, Pete?
什么
What?
毕业后 你打算做啥
When you graduate, what do you think you'll do?
嗯 我不知道 别拷问他啦 老爸
Oh, I don't know. Don't grill him, dad.
随便聊聊而已
Just saying, you know.
当你们上学的时候
All you guys who go to that school
肯定也规划好了自己的未来吧
you pretty much have your life planNed out, right?
没呢 我才高二
Yeah, no, I'm just a sophomore.
彼得在钢铁侠那里实习
Peter has an internship with Tony stark.
我觉得他完全没必要担心
So I think he doesn't have to worry.
真的吗
Really? Mm-hm.
- 史塔克工业 - 挺棒啊
- Stark? - So cool.
你在那具体做些什么呢
Oh. What do you do?
事实上 我已经不在那里实习了
Actually, I don't intern for him anymore.
真的吗 实习有点…
Seriously? Yeah, it got...
无聊了
Boring.
无聊
It was boring?
你还能见到蜘蛛侠呢
You got to hang out with spider-man.
是么 蜘蛛侠
Really? Spider-man?
哇 他是个怎样的人
Wow. What's he like?
他挺好的
Yeah, he's nice.
挺好的人 实在人
Nice man. Solid dude.
嗯…
Hm.
看 好可爱 哇
Look. So cute.
嗯…
Oh.
我以前见过你吧
I've seen you around, right?
在哪里 我们见过…
I mean, somewhere.
声音也有点熟悉…
We've... have we ever...? Because even the voice...
我想 可能是因为 他参加了学术比赛吧
he does academic decathlon with me.
他参加过我的派对
Oh. And he was at my party.
- 啊 - 非常不错的派对
- Ah. - It was a great party.
真的不错
Really great, yeah.
房子很漂亮 很多窗户
Beautiful house, a lot of windows.
你就待了大概2分钟
You were there for, like, two seconds.
没有
That was...
我可待了不止2分钟
I was there longer than two seconds.
你消失了 没有啊
You disappeared. No.
我没消失
No, I did not disappear. Yes, you did.
你消失了 就像你经常一样
You disappeared like you always do.
还有在华盛顿那次也是
Like you did in D.C. too.
华盛顿那件事
That's terrible
可真恐怖啊
what happeNed down there in D.C. though.
你当时吓到了么
Were you scared?
你看到你的老朋友蜘蛛侠出现在电梯的时候
I'll bet you were glad when your old pal spider-man
应该很高兴吧
showed up in the elevator though, huh?
我实际上没有上去
Yeah, well, I actually didn't go up.
我一直在地面上看的
I saw it all from the ground.
他那天来救我们了
Yeah.
我们可真幸运
Very lucky that he was there that day.
蜘蛛侠干得不错
Good old spider-man.
老爸 绿灯啦
Dad, the light.
到啦
Here we are. End of the line.
我们到啦 谢了 老爸
Thanks, dad.
宝贝 你先进去
You head in there, gumdrop.
我和彼得聊点 "私房话"
I'm gonna give Peter the "dad" talk.
别被他吓到了
Don't let him intimidate you.
爱你
Love you.
爱你 宝贝 路上小心哦
Love you, gumdrop. Have a safe flight.
你们好
Hi.
你们真漂亮啊
You guys look so pretty.
她知道吗
Does she know?
知道什么
Know what?
这么说来她不知道了 很好
So she doesn't. Good.
保密工作做得不错 我很佩服你
Close to the vest. I admire that.
我自己也有一些秘密
I've got a few secrets of my own.
你想到了吗
Of all the reasons I didn't want my daughter to date...
反对女儿约会的理由竟然是…
I didn't want my daughter to date...
彼得
Peter,
没有什么比家庭更重要
nothing is more important than family.
你救了我女儿一命
You saved my daughter's life.
我永远不会忘记
I could never forget something like that.
所以 我给你一次机会
So I'm gonna give you one chance.
你听好了
Are you ready?
你走进去
You walk through those doors,
然后忘记发生过的一切
you forget any of this happeNed
然后永远…
and don't you ever,
永远
ever
不要再干涉我的事
interfere with my business again.
要是你再来的话…
'Cause if you do,
我会杀了你…
I'll kill you
还有所有你爱的人
and everybody you love.
我会杀了你
I'll kill you dead.
这样做是为了保护我的家人 彼得
That's what I'll do to protect my family, Pete.
明白了么
Do you understand?
喂
Hey.
我刚刚放了你一马 你应该说些什么来着
I just saved your life. Now what do you say?
谢谢
Thank you.
不用谢
You're welcome.
进去吧 好好
Now, you go on in there,
陪我女儿
you show my daughter a good time, okay?
但也不要太过了
Just not too good.
嘿
Hey.
他和你说啥了
What did he say to you?
我得走了
I've got to go.
对不起
I'm... I'm sorry.
我不该这么对你的
You don't deserve this.
他给了你机会
He gave you a choice.
但是你却不珍惜 什么鬼
You chose wrong. What the hell?
这是什么破衣服
What's with the crappy costume?
我的蛛网发射器
My web-shooters.
开始我还不确定这东西好不好用 但是…
I wasn't sure about this thing at first,
牛啊
but... Damn.
真暴躁
Oh, gross.
为什么他要派你过来 估计你永远都不会知道真相了
Why did he send you here? Guess you'll never know.
射得漂亮
Huh? Nice shot!
漂亮
Yes!
内德 那个有翅膀的人是丽兹的老爸
Ned, the guy with the wings is Liz's dad.
什么 我得告诉史塔克先生
What? I know. I gotta tell Mr. stark.
联系哈皮·霍根 他是史塔克先生的安保主管
Call happy hogan. He's Mr. stark's head of security.
找部电脑 然后追踪我的手机
Get a computer and track my phone for me.
你小心点 快点 我们要在他出城前
Are you gonna be okay? Hurry, we gotta catch him
抓住他
before he leaves town.
那个晚餐真是抱歉 但是…
I'm sorry about dinner,
我知道新鲜的柠檬鲈鱼是啥样的
but I know when branzino's fresh,
那个不新鲜 知道吗
and that was not fresh, okay?
所以…
So... ah!
闪电 我需要借下你的车和电话
Flash, I need your car and your phone.
先生 这车是我老爸的所以我不能给你…
Sir, technically, this is my dad's car, sir, so I can't...
你好 内德 喂喂喂 能听到我吗
Hello, Ned? Hey, hey, can you hear me?
我是内德
Go for Ned.
内德 我需要你追踪我手机的位置
Ned, I need you to track my phone for me.
好 你的手机目前在哪
Yeah, but where is it?
太机智了 他刚刚路过
Genius move. Okay, he just passed
杰克逊大街上的电玩店
the gamestop on Jackson Avenue.
嘿 我在闪电的车上
Hey, where are the headlights on this thing?
这东西的前灯怎么打开 我找找说明
I'm in flash's car. I'll pull the specs.
好的 我开免提
Okay, you're on speakerphone.
你偷了闪电的车 太牛了
You stole flash's car? Awesome.
是啊 确实很牛
Yeah, it's awesome! It's awe...
快让开
oh! Get out of the way!
让开
Get out of the way! Move! Move!
彼得 你还好吧 我之前没有在路上开过车
Peter, are you okay? I've never driven before.
只在停车场练过
Only with may in parking lots.
这可是质的飞跃啊
This is a huge step up. Whoa!
嘿 你联系上哈皮了没
Hey, have you gotten through to happy yet?
我正在联系
Uh, yeah. I'm working on it.
我刚搞定了电话系统
I just gotta backdoor the phone system.
幕后指挥
Guy in the chair.
9分钟后起飞
Takeoff in nine minutes.
哪位 喂 哪位
Hello? Hello? Who is this?
哈皮先生 我是内德 你是谁
Mr. happy, it's Ned. Who?
我是彼得·帕克的助手
I'm an associate of Peter Parker.
他有件很重要的事要告诉你
Got something important to tell you...
你在逗我吧 该死
you gotta be shitting me. Damn.
嘿 内德 你查到怎么打开车前灯了吗
Hey, Ned, how we coming with those headlights?
旋转旋钮 转向方向盘的左边
Round knob to the left of the steering wheel,
顺时针转动 往左么 好了
turn clockwise. Left, okay.
好了 搞定 我的手机到哪里了
Okay, perfect. So where's my phone now?
他停在了布鲁克林的一个旧工业园区
Um... He stopped in an old industrial park in Brooklyn.
什么 没道理啊
What? That makes no sense!
他说他要出城的
I thought he said he was going out of town!
奇怪对了 我联系到哈皮先生了
Weird. Oh, I reached Mr. happy.
我觉得他不大喜欢你啊
Don't think he likes you, by the way.
而且 听起来他好像要搭飞机
Sounded like he was catching a flight.
他说9分钟后起飞
Something about taking off in nine minutes.
什么 他周围都是箱子
What? He was surrounded by boxes.
箱子 今天是搬家的日子
Boxes? It's moving day.
他要抢那架飞机
It's moving day. He's gonna rob that plane.
我要阻止他
I gotta stop him!
好 还有8分钟起飞
All right, wheels up in eight minutes.
我们要装上钢铁侠的旧式反浩克盔甲
We just got to load Tony's old hulkbuster armor,
美国队长的新盾牌模型 和 梅…
prototype for cap's new shield, and the meging...
梅…梅…雷神索尔的魔法腰带
the Meg... the... Thor's magic belt.
好 慢点 你快到了
Okay, slow down. You're getting close.
在你的右边 什么
It's on your right. What?
右转 右转
Turn right! Turn right!
彼得 你还好吧 没事
Peter, are you okay? Yeah.
你继续联系哈皮
Just keep trying to get through to happy.
包在我身上 蜘蛛侠
It's been an honor, spider-man.
你在这里干嘛 不去参加舞会
What are you doing here? There's a dance.
我在看…
I'm looking
小电影
at porn.
嘿
Hey!
吃惊吧
Surprised?
嘿 彼得
Oh, hey, Pete.
我没听见你进来了
I didn't hear you come in.
结束了 我抓住你了
It's over. I've got you.
我知道 我要告诉你 彼得…
You know, i gotta tell you, Pete,
我真的欣赏你的勇气
I really, really admire your grit.
我知道为啥丽兹喜欢你了
I see why Liz likes you.
我真的明白了 你刚到我家的时候
I do. When you first came to the house,
我不大确定 我当时想 "就这小毛孩"
I wasn't sure. I thought, "really?"
但是我现在明白了
But I get it now.
你怎么能这样对她
How could you do this to her?
对她 我没对她做什么 彼得
To her? I'm not doing anything to her, Pete.
我是 "为了" 她做这些事
I'm doing this for her.
嗯 没错
Huh, yeah.
彼得
Peter,
你太年轻了
you're young.
你不理解这个世界怎么运作的
You don't understand how the world works.
没错 但是我知道
Yeah, but I understand
把武器卖给罪犯是错的
that selling weapons to criminals is wrong.
那你觉得 你的钢铁侠兄弟 为什么有钱买下那座大厦
How do you think your buddy stark paid for that tower?
还有他的那些小玩具
Or any of his little toys?
那些人 彼得 那些人
Those people, Pete, those people up there,
高高在上 有钱有势…他们为所欲为
the rich and the powerful, they do whatever they want.
像你和我这样的普通人…
Guys like us, like you and me,
他们不管我们死活
they don't care about us.
我们为他们铺路 给他们卖命
We build their roads and we fight all their wars
但是他们根本不在乎我们
and everything, but they don't care about us.
我们不得不去给他们收拾烂摊子
We have to pick up after 'em.
我们不得不去吃他们的剩饭
We have to eat their table scraps.
世界就是这么运作的
That's how it is.
我知道 你明白我的意思 彼得
I know you know what I'm talking about, Peter.
你跟我说这些干嘛
Why are you telling me this?
因为我希望你能明白这些道理
Because I want you to understand.
而且…
And...
我需要点时间让它起飞
I needed a little time to get her airborne.
不好意思了 彼得
I'm sorry, Peter.
你在说什么啊
What are you talking about?
那玩意都没碰到我
That thing hasn't even touched me yet.
确实 但是还是得说…
True. Then again,
它根本就没打算碰到你
wasn't really trying to.
老大 他们开始启动引擎了
Chief, they're powering up engines.
好 我来了 快点
Okay. Yeah, yeah. Come on, come on, come on.
我的天
Oh, god.
好的 准备好了吗
Okay, ready?
有人吗
Hello!
有人吗 救命…
Please. Hey.
Hey, please. I'm down here.
我被困住了
I'm down here. I'm stuck.
我在下面 我被卡住了 我动不了了…
I'm stuck. I can't move. I can't...
如果你没了装备什么都不是的话
if you're nothing without this suit,
你就不配有装备
then you shouldn't have it.
加油 彼得
Come on, Peter.
加油 蜘蛛侠
Come on, spider-man.
Come on, spider-man!
尝试拦截成功
Launch for intercept. Green light. Green light.
很好
Oh, yeah.
反射隐身板开启
Retroreflective panels engaged.
检测到飞机了
Got a visual on the plane,
但是感觉有些阻力
but I'm feeling a little resistance.
大概是因为那个新的涡轮机吧
It's probably just drag on the new turbines.
小心那些监控摄像头
Look out for the cloaking cameras.
待在盲区中
Stay in the blind spots.
噢 天哪
Oh, my god! Oh, my god!
部署高空密封装置
Deploy high-altitude vacuum seal.
这玩意最好管用 梅森
This better work, Mason.
相信我 老板只要拿到其中一个箱子
Trust me, boss, even one of those boxes
我们就发财了 是啊
and we are set for life. Yeah.
嘿
Hey! Ah! Whew.
你有30秒进入驾驶舱
You have 30 seconds to get to the cockpit
关掉安全系统
and override their security.
复制应答器信号
Cloning transponder signal.
启动诱饵无人机
Launching decoy drone.
输入新坐标
Entering new coordinates.
很好 飞机还在航线上吧
Good, so it's on its way?
是的 先生 在航线上 好的 谢谢
Yes, sir, right on course. Okay, thank you.
好了
All right.
全是宝贝
Hot dog.
真是个难忘的返校节…
Just a typical homecoming
在一架隐形机的外面…
on the outside of an invisible jet... ah!
和我的女朋友的老爸斗
Fighting my girlfriend's dad.
哦 天哪
Oh, god!
这招居然管用
Whew. I can't believe that worked.
老大 老大 飞机正在下坠 快离开那里
Chief, they're losing altitude. Get out of there.
我才不会空手而归
I'm not going home empty-handed.
哦 天哪
Oh, my god.
快离开那里 你在干嘛
- Get out of there. - What are you doing?
快转弯 快转弯
Please turn! Please turn!
嘿 佩德罗
Hey, Pedro.
找到了
Bingo.
你的翅膀…
Your wingsuit.
你的翅膀要爆炸啦
Your wingsuit's gonna explode!
回家吧 彼得
Time to go home, Pete.
我在救你
I'm trying to save you!
不
No!
No.
不
No!
真的太疯狂了
like, it was just crazy.
他就…
He was just, like...
你就…
And you were like, "ah!"
然后我就这样打了他…
And then I just hit him with the "fffew."
简直太…哦 我的天哪
It was so... oh, my god.
你救了我
You saved me.
太酷了
It was awesome.
嘿 丽兹
Hey, Liz.
我会想你的
I'm gonna miss you.
再见
Bye.
丽兹…
Liz.
丽兹 我很抱歉
Liz, look, I'm so sorry.
你抱歉过很多次了
You say that a lot.
这次抱歉什么
What are you sorry for this time?
舞会的事吗
The dance?
那确实很过分
That was a pretty crappy thing to do.
是的 但是…你老爸
Well, yeah, but i... i mean, your dad...
很难想象 你经历了这么多事情
I can't imagine what you're going through.
如果有什么我可以帮忙的…
If there's anything i can do to help...
我们要帮到俄勒冈去了
I guess we're moving to Oregon.
妈妈说那里不错 所以挺好的
Mom says it's nice there, so that's cool.
总之 我爸受审的时候
Anyways, dad doesn't want us here
不希望我们在这里 所以…
during the trial, so...
丽兹 我…我…
Liz, i... i...
再见 彼得
bye, Peter.
无论发生什么
Whatever's going on with you,
我希望你都能搞定
I hope you figure it out.
祝贺我们获得学术比赛全国冠军
Congratulations, decathlon national champions.
我一会就得把它放回奖杯柜
I'm gonna have to put this back in the trophy case soon,
但是为了在训练的时候激励大家
but just for motivation right now at this practice.
我就提前说了
I'm a little ahead of the game,
明年我们需要一个新队长
but we will need a new team captain next year.
我提名米歇尔
So I am appointing Michelle.
好
Yeah!
谢谢
Uh, thank you.
我朋友叫我MJ
My... my friends call me mj.
我以为你没有朋友呢
I thought you didn't have any friends.
我确实没有
I didn't.
- 我得走了 - 嘿 你去哪里
- I gotta go. - Hey, where you going?
你在隐瞒什么呢 彼得
What are you hiding, Peter?
我开玩笑的 你不用告诉我 拜拜
I'm just kidding. I don't care. Bye.
好吧 我们应该练习下
All right, so we should run some drills.
行
Yeah.
嘿 哈皮 你在这里做什么
Hey, happy. What... what are you doing here?
我欠你个人情
I really owe you one.
我不知道没了这份工作咋办
I don't know what I would do without this job.
我是说 我认识托尼以前…
I mean, before I met Tony...
你在这里呆了多久了
so how long you been here?
呆到我都觉得尴尬了 老板要见你
Long enough to be awkward. Boss wants to see you.
他也在这里
Is he here too?
在厕所里 不 他在新的总部
In the toilet? No, he's upstate.
新的总部 你说的那个新复仇者基地
Upstate? Like, upstate-upstate?
是的 走吧
Yeah, let's go.
看看四周
Take a look.
是不是挺不错的
It's pretty impressive, huh?
这里刚刚完工
They just finished remodeling the whole thing.
- 你不是每天都能见到这个吧 - 噢 你们来啦
- You don't see that every day. - Oh, there they are.
- 路上顺利吧 - 很好
- How was the ride up? - Good.
我要和孩子单独谈谈
Give me a minute with the kid.
- 真的 - 是的
- Seriously? - Yeah.
我要和他谈谈
I got to talk to the kid.
我就在附近等着
I'll be close behind.
走远点吧 走远一点比较好
How about a loose follow?
走远一点比较好
All right? Boundaries are good.
不好意思 之前收回你的装备
Sorry I took your suit.
那是你活该
I mean, you had it coming.
其实 这么看来 我收回的时机很合适
Actually, it turns out it was the perfect
爱之深责之切嘛 对吧
tough-love moment that you needed, right?
驱使你继续努力 你觉得呢
To urge you on? Wouldn't you think?
- 你觉得呢 - 我…
- Don't you think? - I guess.
你回答 "对" 就行了
Let's just say it was.
史塔克先生 我真的…
Mr. stark, I really...
你当时确实搞砸了很多事
you screwed the pooch hard, bigtime.
但是后来 你做了正确的事
But then you did the right thing.
打个比方 你把狗带到了免费的诊所
Took the dog to the free clinic,
然后又养了混血小狗…
you raised the hybrid puppies.
好吧 这个比方不大恰当
All right, not my best analogy.
我之前看错你了
I was wrong about you.
我想 给你一些指导…
I think, with a little more mentoring,
你会是团队里的得力干将
you could be a real asset to the team.
- 团队 - 是的 总之…
To the... to the team? Yeah. Anyway,
这扇门后面有差不多50名记者
there's about 50 reporters behind that door.
真正的记者 不是那些写博客的
Real ones, not bloggers.
等你准备好…
When you're ready,
我想让你试下这个
why don't you try that on?
我要向世界宣布
And I'll introduce the world
复仇者联盟最新成员
to the newest official member of the avengers:
蜘蛛侠
Spider-man.
我…
I... heh.
好好欣赏下吧
Yeah, give that a look.
发布会以后 哈皮会带你
So after the press conference,
去你的房间 你的新住处
happy will show you to your room, your new quarters.
他住哪间 他住幻视隔壁吧
Where's he between? He's next to vision?
嗯 幻视不怎么在意门
Yeah, vision's not big on doors.
- 很好 - 也不在乎墙
- It's fun. - Or walls.
正适合你呢
You'll fit right in.
谢谢你 史塔克先生
Thank you, Mr. stark,
但是 我…我挺好的
but I'm... I'm good.
你挺好的 好 你怎么好了
You're good? How are you good?
我是说 我这段时间
Well, I mean, I'd rather just stay
宁愿脚踏实地
on the ground for a little while.
做一个友善的邻家蜘蛛侠
Friendly neighborhood spider-man.
总有些普通人需要帮助 对吧
Somebody's got to look out for the little guy, right?
你要拒绝我么
You're turning me down?
你最好再考虑一下 看看那个装备
You better think about this. Look at that.
再看看我
Look at me.
最后问你一遍 留还是不留
Last chance. Yes or no?
- 不留 - 好
- No. - Okay.
就像斯普林斯汀一样
It's kind of a Springsteen-y,
当个草根英雄 就是我欣赏的那种作风啊
working-class hero vibe that I dig.
哈皮会送你回家
Ah, happy will take you home.
- 对吧 - 是的
- Yeah? - Yeah.
你介意在车上等下吗 给我一会儿
Mind waiting in the car? I need a minute.
谢谢你 史塔克先生
Thank you, Mr. stark.
没事的 帕克先生 不客气
Yes, Mr. Parker, very well.
再见了
See you around. Okay.
这是个测试吧
That was a test, right?
门后面没人吧
There's nobody back there?
对 你通过了
Yes, you passed.
快走吧 小屁孩
All right, skedaddle there, young buck.
谢谢 史塔克先生 谢谢你
Thank you, Mr. stark. Thank you.
嗯 也谢谢你啦
Yeah, thank you.
跟你说过的 他是个不错的孩子
Told you he was a good kid.
小辣椒 小辣椒
Pepper! Pepper!
那孩子呢
Where's the kid?
- 他走了 - 大家都等着呢
- He left. - Everybody's waiting.
其实 他做了一个很成熟的决定
He actually made a really mature choice.
他刚刚让我们大吃一惊
It just surprised the heck out of us.
你们是不是搞砸了
Did you guys screw this up?
他让那小孩在车里等他
He told the kid to wait in the car.
你在逗我吧 那可有一屋子人
Are you kidding me? I have a room full of people waiting
等着我们的重要声明 那我要怎么解释
for some big announcement. What am I gonna tell them?
想点办法啊 要不…
Think of something. How about, um,
哈皮 你带了那个戒指吗
hap, you still got that ring?
我…
Do i... i...
- 就是那个订婚戒指 - 这还用说
- The engagement ring. - Are you kidding?
从2008年起 我就一直把它带在身边
I've been carrying this since 2008.
很好
Okay.
我觉得 我能想出比这个更好的主意
I think I can think of something better than that.
这能给我们争取些时间嘛
Well, it would buy us a little time.
你这拖得也是够久了
Like we need time.
你居然一直随身带着这个戒指 简直难以置信
I can't believe you have that thing in your pocket.
亲爱的 要不要我帮你开门
Let me to get the door for you, hon?
明白了
I got it.
嘿 梅 晚饭做好了吗
Aunt may, did you do dinner already?
这是属于你的
- 钢铁侠
梅
May?
什么鬼
What the f...?!
蜘蛛侠：英雄归来
看看这是谁啊
Look who it is.
真是巧啊 你跟我
What are the odds you and I'd end up
进了同一间号子啊
at the same summer camp?
放松
Relax.
我不是来找你的麻烦的
This? It's not on you.
我是来问问那个蜘蛛男的事
It's on our little spider friend.
我外面有些兄弟
I've got some boys on the outside
很乐意去拜访他一下
who would love to meet him.
你懂的 拍几张照片
You know, take a picture,
割破喉咙 把他的头扔进烘干机
slice his throat, put his head in a dryer.
我听说
And I heard a rumor...
你认识他啊
You know who he is.
如果我知道他是谁
If I knew who he was,
他肯定已经死透了
he'd already be dead.
图姆斯 你的家人来了
Toomes, your family's here!
大家好 我是美国队长 我现在来谈谈
Hi, I'm captain America, here to talk to you
一位士兵或是一位学生
about one of the most valuable traits
所应具有的宝贵品质
a soldier or student can have.
耐心
Patience.
有时候 耐心是胜利的关键
Sometimes Patience is the key to victory.
有些时候 耐心也改变不了什么
Sometimes it leads to very little
在这种时候 似乎耐心没什么价值
and it seems like it's not worth it.
你会想知道
And you wonder
为什么等待了这么久
why you waited so long
结局却如此令人失望
for something so disappointing.
还要我说多久这样的废话
How many more of these?
蜘蛛侠还会归来